<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>/dev/yash/notes</title>
    <link>https://yashagarwal.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on /dev/yash/notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution - NonCommercial - ShareAlike 4.0 International</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 22:02:08 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yashagarwal.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 - Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/12/2018---year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 22:02:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/12/2018---year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>The year 2018 has been quite a roller coaster year for me. I saw many ups and downs, many successes and many failures, faced many challenges on the personal front and struggled to keep myself on track. I have been working hard on improving my lifestyle (not materialistically) for the last few years, and the benefits have begun to show up now. This year was a pinnacle in that aspect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Millionaire Booklet - Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018/12/the-millionaire-booklet---review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 09:50:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018/12/the-millionaire-booklet---review/</guid>
      <description>Rating: 3.7 / 5 
A friend suggested me to read this book. It was my first audiobook, and my experience is a mixed one. I am not a very good retainer of information while listening to something when compared with my retention capabilities while reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Will Teach You to Be Rich - Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018/12/i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich---review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 08:30:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018/12/i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich---review/</guid>
      <description>Rating: 4 / 5 
It was my first book on the topic of personal finance. I am entirely new to managing money, so I thought it would be a good idea to gain some knowledge before trying anything crazy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Code Book - Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018/12/the-code-book---review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 19:04:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018/12/the-code-book---review/</guid>
      <description>Rating: 5 / 5 
I was interested in Cryptography and Number Theory during my undergraduate studies so reading the history of Cryptography in this book was intriguing for me. The author has done excellent work in making sure that even an uninitiated person in Cryptography can understand and appreciate the importance of work done in this field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Secrets of Vishnu - Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018/11/7-secrets-of-vishnu---review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 14:00:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018/11/7-secrets-of-vishnu---review/</guid>
      <description>Rating: 4.5 / 5 
For me, reading this book was to look at the things that I already knew, from a different perspective — not necessarily the view that I agree with. This book starts with Mohini and goes on to tell the stories of all the mainstream avatars of Vishnu and what the significance of those avatars was, in their respective time periods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Quantum Theory - Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018/11/introducing-quantum-theory---review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 20:31:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018/11/introducing-quantum-theory---review/</guid>
      <description>Rating: 4.2 / 5 
There was a time when I used to despise Physics. I still do not know the exact reason behind this feeling because I was much interest in Physics in general. Perhaps the mathematical questions of JEE put me off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rozabal Line - Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018/11/the-rozabal-line---review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 12:00:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018/11/the-rozabal-line---review/</guid>
      <description>Rating: 3.8 / 5 
It was an exciting read for me. I must say the amount of research done by the author is really commendable. Given the topic of this work, the author comes very close to getting everything right, but eventually, he misses the mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning a New Journey</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/08/beginning-a-new-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 21:16:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/08/beginning-a-new-journey/</guid>
      <description>When I was in eighth (or was it ninth?) class, one of our teachers asked in the class, what do you want to become in your life? People said a lot of things. When my turn came up, I stood up and said, “Mein software engineer banana chahta hu” (I want to become a software engineer). It was not that I was genuinely interested in Computers. When I look back now, I realize that it was my cousins who affected my choice (in an indirect way) and their achievements fascinated me to aim at this particular career choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Good and Bad about CSED of NIT-C</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/the-good-and-bad-about-csed-of-nit-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 17:59:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/the-good-and-bad-about-csed-of-nit-c/</guid>
      <description>Four years ago, in this very month of June, JEE Mains results were out. I had screwed up my JEE Advanced, so I had to settle for an NIT. My AIR was good enough to get me a seat of Computer Science and Engineering in any of the NITs except the first three (at that time Trichy, Warangal, and Surathkal). I was skeptical about going to NIT Calicut because of its distance from my native place, so NIT Allahabad was the most suitable choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battery Notifications in i3</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/battery-notifications-in-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 09:45:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/battery-notifications-in-i3/</guid>
      <description>I am using i3 window manager for last seven months, and it has been a pleasant and productive experience so far. There were a few hiccups here and there, but that is expected with such minimalistic setups. One thing that I never noticed was the lack of notifications on critical battery levels. For last few months, my laptop battery was discharging to 0% all the time. Probably this proved to be too fatal for my battery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistakes That I Made in NITC</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/mistakes-that-i-made-in-nitc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:21:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/mistakes-that-i-made-in-nitc/</guid>
      <description>Now that I am graduated from NIT Calicut, one more chapter of my life is over. It is time to move on to the next page, but before I begin that phase, I thought it would be nice, to sum up, the experience that I gathered in NIT Calicut. The last four years have been great for me. I learned a lot of new life lessons, but there were some decisions which I could have avoided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxy Your Requests to the Backend Server With Grunt</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/05/proxy-your-requests-to-the-backend-server-with-grunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 17:14:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/05/proxy-your-requests-to-the-backend-server-with-grunt/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published on zeolearn.
If you are working on large projects, it is undoubtedly a good idea to have a build script or some task scripts to help to automate some of the repetitive parts of the development process. For JavaScript projects, Grunt serves the similar purpose. It is a JavaScript task/build runner that is written on top of NodeJS. Grunt can help you with automatically minifying your JavaScript or CSS files, reload your browser on every file change, can show you a comprehensive list of JavaScript errors, compile your SASS/LESS files into CSS files automatically and many other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Drozer Modules</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/05/writing-drozer-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 17:10:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/05/writing-drozer-modules/</guid>
      <description>This post is a result of my experimentation with Drozer. Drozer is a security testing framework for Android, developed by MWR Labs. According the Drozer&amp;rsquo;s official documentation:
 Drozer allows you to assume the role of an Android app and interact with other apps. It can do anything that an installed application can do, such as make use of Android’s Inter-Process Communication (IPC) mechanism and interact with the underlying operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So I Applied for GSoC</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/so-i-applied-for-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 20:58:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/so-i-applied-for-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>I first heard about Google Summer of Code (GSoC) in my second year (2016). It was quite fascinating to know that such a program exists (possibly because of that super attractive amount of money, $5500 at that time). I researched about it and sent emails to some mentors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSSMeet&#39;18</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/fossmeet18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 11:57:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/fossmeet18/</guid>
      <description>I know I am very late in writing this post. It has been almost one and half months since the last edition of FOSSMeet is over. I have been a part of FOSSMeet both as a participant and a volunteer. I want to share some of my observations, views, and suggestions through this post. I intend to keep a memory of my most favorite event of NIT Calicut. Juniors can read this post and think about ways to improve FOSSCell and FOSSMeet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deactivated My Facebook Account</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/deactivated-my-facebook-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 21:00:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/deactivated-my-facebook-account/</guid>
      <description>Today, I deactivated my Facebook account again. For last few days, I started feeling that I am using Facebook excessively. That was affecting some other works. It was even affecting my public life. I was using Facebook day in and day out. Today when I woke up in the morning, I first opened Facebook and didn&amp;rsquo;t leave my bed for one hour. I realized that I have wasted one hour merely browsing through useless stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop a Theme for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/develop-a-theme-for-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 11:27:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/develop-a-theme-for-hugo/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published on zeolearn.
Introduction In this tutorial, I will show you how to create a basic Hugo theme. I assume that you are familiar with basic HTML, and how to write content in markdown. I will be explaining the working of Hugo and how it uses Go templating language and how you can use these templates to organize your content. As this post will be focusing mainly on Hugo&amp;rsquo;s working, I will not be covering CSS here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Domain</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/02/my-new-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 10:10:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/02/my-new-domain/</guid>
      <description>I bought a new domain a few days back - yashagarwal.in. I was trying to buy this domain for last two years, but it was already taken. My previous domain, yashagarwal.me that I got for free via GitHub education pack was good enough for me, but the thought that I own a domain which is a top-level domain of some other country was in itself something which I was not comfortable with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syncing Time on Windows &amp; GNU/Linux Dual Boot Setups</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/02/syncing-time-on-windows--gnu/linux-dual-boot-setups/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 12:54:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/02/syncing-time-on-windows--gnu/linux-dual-boot-setups/</guid>
      <description>This post is going to be one among those, that I have written for my own reference. Whatever I am going to mention in this post, is not new. Everything has already been said and written many times on many websites and Linux forums.
So I will start with explaining the problem. When you try to dual boot your machine to run both GNU/Linux and Windows operating systems, you might have noticed that the time is not same in both the operating systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why a Sanskrit Shloka?</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/why-a-sanskrit-shloka/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 20:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/why-a-sanskrit-shloka/</guid>
      <description>श्रूयतां धर्मसर्वस्वं श्रुत्वा चाप्यवधार्यताम्।
आत्मनः प्रतिकूलानि परेषां न समाचरेत्।। If the entire Dharma can be said in a few words, then it is — that which is unfavorable to us, do not do that to others.
— Padmapuraana, shrushti 19/357–358
 So when you landed on this blog, the first thing you might have noticed is that the home page of this blog has a Sanskrit shloka. Many people ask me, why did I choose to display a Sanskrit shloka on my blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux Installation Guide Part 2</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/arch-linux-installation-guide-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 15:45:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/arch-linux-installation-guide-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will continue from my last post and set up my newly installed Arch Linux for daily use. I am going to install some applications that I use on a day to day basis. Some of these applications are required for my current configuration setup to work properly. The choice of applications is highly opinionated and your preferences might be different.
Note: If you had gone for installation via SSH option, then I would suggest you to edit your sshd_config file and disable root login.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux Installation Guide Part 1</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/arch-linux-installation-guide-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 21:49:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/arch-linux-installation-guide-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Arch Linux is a Linux distribution known for its not-so-beginner-friendly command line installer, no ready-to-use system after installation and requirement of above average knowledge of command line. However, Arch Linux allows me to set up a system in my desired state in shortest possible time with least effort. This is why I keep coming back to Arch Linux even after some of its annoyances.
This guide is written primarily for my reference, as someone who has installed Arch Linux several times, I still can&amp;rsquo;t remember all the installation steps perfectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Own Configuration Manager</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/my-own-configuration-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 11:23:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/my-own-configuration-manager/</guid>
      <description>I have been using Linux since I was in my second year of undergraduate. My experiments with the dotfiles (configuration files) also started at the same time. For the uninformed, in Linux, it is common to configure a lot of settings and configurations within dotfiles. Dotfiles are files in a Linux user&amp;rsquo;s home directory that begin with a dot or a full-stop character. This dot indicates to the operating system, that these files are used to store the settings of programs like vim or shells like bash or fish to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 - The Best Till Now</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/12/2017---the-best-till-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 23:19:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/12/2017---the-best-till-now/</guid>
      <description>If I have to define 2017 in one word, that would be amazing. This year has been a life-changing year for me. I learned a lot of new things, had some excellent experience in the company of amazing people, had a great time in my academic life and SSL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up SSH Agent in i3</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/12/setting-up-ssh-agent-in-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 20:21:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/12/setting-up-ssh-agent-in-i3/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will write about the procedure to correctly setup SSH and GPG agents in the i3 window manager. To follow this post, you need to have ssh-keys and your private GPG keys ready. If you do not already have these keys with you, I will describe the process of creating the keys.
SSH Generating an SSH key pair provides you with a public key and a private key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up ALM Octane with Docker Compose</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/12/setting-up-alm-octane-with-docker-compose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 20:53:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/12/setting-up-alm-octane-with-docker-compose/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I got a chance to setup ALM Octane on one of my university server for a course project. From the support page of ALM Octane:
 ALM Octane is a web-based application lifecycle management platform that enables teams to collaborate easily, manage the product delivery pipeline, and visualise the impact of changes.
 Precursor My department insists on using open source software (a plus point, indeed !). But ALM Octane has Oracle DB/MSSQL as a dependency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Hindi Fonts in Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/10/fixing-hindi-fonts-in-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 21:55:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/10/fixing-hindi-fonts-in-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>When viewing Hindi content in any browser in Arch Linux, the rendering looks weird.
    before applying the fix
    Doesn&amp;rsquo;t look good right! I&amp;rsquo;ll try to fix this issue in this post. You might need to install the appropriate font support in Arch Linux before applying this fix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mounting NTFS partitions on Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/03/mounting-ntfs-partitions-on-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 10:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/03/mounting-ntfs-partitions-on-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I installed Arch Linux once again. A clean, bloat free desktop with Budgie Desktop environment with some must have open source tools. Everything worked fine except WiFi and some minor bugs in Budgie(I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether it is a bug in Budgie or just a wrong setting). I also faced the problem of mounting Windows NTFS volumes on user&amp;rsquo;s wish. Arch Linux wiki has details about how to auto mount partitions on start-up, but I had a tough time to find out what exactly needs to be done to simulate the behavior of Ubuntu-like distribution on the mounting of NTFS drives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSSMeet&#39;17</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/03/fossmeet17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 21:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/03/fossmeet17/</guid>
      <description>One more edition of FOSSMeet&amp;rsquo;17 was successfully organized in NIT Calicut recently. As an active member of the organizing team of this year&amp;rsquo;s edition (though I sidelined myself at the end) and a keen but silent observer, I want to share my experience, ideas, and some observations through this post.
Marketing Website We started planning next edition of FOSSMeet sometime around September. Not many people were interested in the planning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Hugo automatic deployment to Github with Wercker</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/02/setting-up-hugo-automatic-deployment-to-github-with-wercker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 13:37:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/02/setting-up-hugo-automatic-deployment-to-github-with-wercker/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I again migrated my blog from Pelican to Hugo. So till now, I have experimented with Wordpress, Jekyll, Pelican and Hugo. Without any doubt, Hugo is the simplest to setup. This time, I have setup Hugo in Windows, as I think, in my system, I reinstall Windows OS much less frequently than the Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Python Development Environments</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/10/setting-up-python-development-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/10/setting-up-python-development-environments/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was searching for Python projects on Github for contribution. Every single project I found, had a thing common among them. In every project&amp;rsquo;s contribution guide, it was asked to set up the virtual environment for the project. What the heck is this virtual environment and how does it work?
As a beginner to open source projects, the problem I faced, in the beginning, was how to set up the development environments for the projects I was looking at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Arch Linux setup with Openbox</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/06/custom-arch-linux-setup-with-openbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/06/custom-arch-linux-setup-with-openbox/</guid>
      <description>After my summer vacation started, I bought a new laptop and the first thing I did was to install Arch Linux on it. After a standard arch installation procedure, I started putting together my own desktop environment starting with ArchLinux and Openbox and then piecing all pieces together to build a proper desktop environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A good Sublime Text Setup</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/a-good-sublime-text-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 10:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/a-good-sublime-text-setup/</guid>
      <description>So, after a hectic day, good news finally came. I have been selected as a Lab Administrator for the Software Systems Lab of my college. Cheers!!!
Let&amp;#8217;s come to our today&amp;#8217;s topic on configuring Sublime Text Settings.
There is just one rule you must follow while designing your own editor preference configuration.
 Don&amp;#8217;t put any lines in your configuration that you don&amp;#8217;t understand.
 You will find tons of online tutorials that contains all kinds of awesome hacks to make your sublime text experience better but the worst way to make your development environment better is just to borrow the configuration from someone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching the goal</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/searching-the-goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/searching-the-goal/</guid>
      <description>A boy, probably of age 16, just cleared his 10th board exam. He saw people working on computers, and that fascinated him. So he had only one ambition. You got it, right? One fine day, suddenly his friend&amp;#8217;s mother asked, &amp;#8220; So what about the future? You are going to enter in class 11th. It is the right time to decide about your future. What do you want to become, a doctor or an engineer?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wanna get insulted by sudo</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/wanna-get-insulted-by-sudo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 12:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/wanna-get-insulted-by-sudo/</guid>
      <description>You might have tried many Linux easters eggs for fun, but you are going to love this hack which makes `sudo` insult you. Confused what I am talking about? Here, take a look at this gif to get an idea of how `sudo` can insult you for typing in the incorrect password.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>whoami</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/whoami/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/whoami/</guid>
      <description>Hi there, I am Yash (y-uh-sh) 👋.
I am a computer programmer interested in network security, cryptography, and distributed systems.
I love trying new operating systems, learning new programming languages and ricing my Linux Desktop.
Other than computers, I am interested in economics, books, writing, history and philosophy. Although I do not prefer discussing my thoughts in public spaces, one to one is always an option.
I work as a Software Engineer at Cisco Systems in Bangalore.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>