<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>/dev/yash/notes</title>
    <link>https://yashhere.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on /dev/yash/notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 10:30:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yashhere.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mounting NTFS partitions on Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/03/mounting-ntfs-partitions-on-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 10:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/03/mounting-ntfs-partitions-on-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I installed Arch Linux once again. A clean, bloat free desktop with Budgie Desktop environment with some must have open source tools. Everything worked fine except WiFi and some minor bugs in Budgie(I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether it is a bug in Budgie or just a wrong setting). I also faced the problem of mounting Windows NTFS volumes on user&amp;rsquo;s wish. Arch Linux wiki has details about how to auto mount partitions on start-up, but I had a tough time to find out what exactly needs to be done to simulate the behavior of Ubuntu-like distribution on the mounting of NTFS drives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSSMeet&#39;17</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/03/fossmeet17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 21:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/03/fossmeet17/</guid>
      <description>One more edition of FOSSMeet&amp;rsquo;17 was successfully organized in NIT Calicut recently. As an active member of the organizing team of this year&amp;rsquo;s edition (though I sidelined myself at the end) and a keen but salient observer, I want to share my experience, ideas, and some observations through this post.
Marketing Website We started planning about next edition of FOSSMeet sometime around September. Not many people were interested in the planning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Hugo automatic deployment to Github with Wercker</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/02/setting-up-hugo-automatic-deployment-to-github-with-wercker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 13:37:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/02/setting-up-hugo-automatic-deployment-to-github-with-wercker/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I again migrated my blog from Pelican to Hugo. So till now, I have experimented with Wordpress, Jekyll, Pelican and Hugo. Without any doubt, Hugo is the simplest to setup. This time, I have setup Hugo in Windows, as I think, in my system, I reinstall Windows OS much less frequently than the Linux. So that way, it will be less pain for me to set up the blog again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Python Development Environments</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2016/10/setting-up-python-development-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2016/10/setting-up-python-development-environments/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was searching for Python projects on Github for contribution. Every single project I found, had a thing common among them. In every project&amp;rsquo;s contribution guide, it was asked to set up the virtual environment for the project. What the heck is this virtual environment and how does it work?
As a beginner to open source projects, the problem I faced, in the beginning, was how to set up the development environments for the projects I was looking at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Arch Linux setup with Openbox</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2016/06/custom-arch-linux-setup-with-openbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2016/06/custom-arch-linux-setup-with-openbox/</guid>
      <description>After my summer vacation started, I bought a new laptop and the first thing I did was to install Arch Linux on it. After a standard arch installation procedure, I started putting together my own desktop environment starting with ArchLinux and Openbox and then piecing all pieces together to build a proper desktop environment. Building a desktop this way really follows the Unix Methodology; have softwares that each do one thing well, and when you put them together you get something amazing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A good Sublime Text Setup</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2016/04/a-good-sublime-text-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 10:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2016/04/a-good-sublime-text-setup/</guid>
      <description>So, after a hactic day, a good news finally came. I have been selected as a Lab Administrator for the Software Systems Lab of my college. Cheers!!!
Let&amp;#8217;s come to our today&amp;#8217;s topic on configuring Sublime Text Settings.
There is just one rule you must follow while designing your own editor preference configuration.
 Don&amp;#8217;t put any lines in your configuration that you don&amp;#8217;t understand.
 You will find tons of online tutorials that contains all kinds of awesome hacks to make your sublime text experience better but the worst way to make your development environment better is to just borrow the configuration from someone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching the goal</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2016/04/searching-the-goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2016/04/searching-the-goal/</guid>
      <description>A boy, probably of age 16, just cleared his 10th board exam. He saw people working on computers and that fascinated him. So he had only one ambition. You got it, right? One fine day, suddenly his friend&amp;#8217;s mother asked, &amp;#8220;So what about the future? You are going to enter in class 11th. It is the right time to decide about your future. What do you want to become, a doctor or an engineer?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wanna get insulted by sudo</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2016/04/wanna-get-insulted-by-sudo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 12:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2016/04/wanna-get-insulted-by-sudo/</guid>
      <description>You might have tried many linux easters eggs for fun, but you are going to love this hack which makes sudo insult you. Confused what I am talking about? Here, take a look at this gif to get a idea of how sudo can insult you for typing in the incorrect password. Now you might be thinking, why would anyone want to take insult? Afterall, nobody likes being insulted. For me, it is just another way to have fun with linux, and anyway this is way better than the plain &amp;#8220;You entered a wrong password&amp;#8221; error message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Speak less than you know; have more than you show.
 Hi there,
I am Yash Agarwal(यश अग्रवाल, y-uh-sh). I am currently studying Computer Science and Engineering at NIT Calicut, India. I love trying new operating systems, new tech, and new programming languages. Well, pretty much everything remotely related to the tech.
People say that I don&#39;t smile much. That&#39;s somewhat true. I am not a camera friendly person. I have very few photos where I am smiling.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>