<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on /dev/yash/notes</title>
    <link>https://yashagarwal.in/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on /dev/yash/notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution - NonCommercial - ShareAlike 4.0 International</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 09:45:46 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Battery Notifications in i3</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/battery-notifications-in-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 09:45:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/battery-notifications-in-i3/</guid>
      <description>I am using i3 window manager for last seven months, and it has been a pleasant and productive experience so far. There were a few hiccups here and there, but that is expected with such minimalistic setups. One thing that I never noticed was the lack of notifications on critical battery levels. For last few months, my laptop battery was discharging to 0% all the time. Probably this proved to be too fatal for my battery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxy Your Requests to the Backend Server With Grunt</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/05/proxy-your-requests-to-the-backend-server-with-grunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 17:14:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/05/proxy-your-requests-to-the-backend-server-with-grunt/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published on zeolearn.
If you are working on large projects, it is undoubtedly a good idea to have a build script or some task scripts to help to automate some of the repetitive parts of the development process. For JavaScript projects, Grunt serves the similar purpose. It is a JavaScript task/build runner that is written on top of NodeJS. Grunt can help you with automatically minifying your JavaScript or CSS files, reload your browser on every file change, can show you a comprehensive list of JavaScript errors, compile your SASS/LESS files into CSS files automatically and many other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So I Applied for GSoC</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/so-i-applied-for-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 20:58:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/so-i-applied-for-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>I first heard about Google Summer of Code (GSoC) in my second year (2016). It was quite fascinating to know that such a program exists (possibly because of that super attractive amount of money, $5500 at that time). I researched about it and sent emails to some mentors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Own Configuration Manager</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/my-own-configuration-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 11:23:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/my-own-configuration-manager/</guid>
      <description>I have been using Linux since I was in my second year of undergraduate. My experiments with the dotfiles (configuration files) also started at the same time. For the uninformed, in Linux, it is common to configure a lot of settings and configurations within dotfiles. Dotfiles are files in a Linux user&amp;rsquo;s home directory that begin with a dot or a full-stop character. This dot indicates to the operating system, that these files are used to store the settings of programs like vim or shells like bash or fish to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>