<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>I3 on /dev/yash/notes</title>
    <link>https://yashagarwal.in/tags/i3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in I3 on /dev/yash/notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution - NonCommercial - ShareAlike 4.0 International</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 09:45:46 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/i3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Battery Notifications in i3</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/battery-notifications-in-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 09:45:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/battery-notifications-in-i3/</guid>
      <description>I am using i3 window manager for last seven months, and it has been a pleasant and productive experience so far. There were a few hiccups here and there, but that is expected with such minimalistic setups. One thing that I never noticed was the lack of notifications on critical battery levels. For last few months, my laptop battery was discharging to 0% all the time. Probably this proved to be too fatal for my battery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux Installation Guide Part 2</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/arch-linux-installation-guide-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 15:45:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/arch-linux-installation-guide-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will continue from my last post and set up my newly installed Arch Linux for daily use. I am going to install some applications that I use on a day to day basis. Some of these applications are required for my current configuration setup to work properly. The choice of applications is highly opinionated and your preferences might be different.
Note: If you had gone for installation via SSH option, then I would suggest you to edit your sshd_config file and disable root login.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux Installation Guide Part 1</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/arch-linux-installation-guide-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 21:49:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/arch-linux-installation-guide-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Arch Linux is a Linux distribution known for its not-so-beginner-friendly command line installer, no ready-to-use system after installation and requirement of above average knowledge of command line. However, Arch Linux allows me to set up a system in my desired state in shortest possible time with least effort. This is why I keep coming back to Arch Linux even after some of its annoyances.
This guide is written primarily for my reference, as someone who has installed Arch Linux several times, I still can&amp;rsquo;t remember all the installation steps perfectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up SSH Agent in i3</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/12/setting-up-ssh-agent-in-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 20:21:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/12/setting-up-ssh-agent-in-i3/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will write about the procedure to correctly setup SSH and GPG agents in the i3 window manager. To follow this post, you need to have ssh-keys and your private GPG keys ready. If you do not already have these keys with you, I will describe the process of creating the keys.
SSH Generating an SSH key pair provides you with a public key and a private key.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>