<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
    <generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.68.3">Hugo</generator><title type="html"><![CDATA[Write-ups on /dev/yash/notes]]></title>
    
        <subtitle type="html"><![CDATA[The directory of my thoughts]]></subtitle>
    
    
    
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HTML" />
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups/index.xml" rel="alternate" type="application/rss+xml" title="RSS" />
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" title="Atom" />
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups/jf2feed.json" rel="alternate" type="application/jf2feed+json" title="jf2feed" />
    <updated>2020-04-04T10:53:07+00:00</updated>
    
    
    <author>
            <name>Yash Agarwal</name>
            
                <email>yashagarwaljpr@gmail.com</email>
            </author>
    
        <id>https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups/</id>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[2019 - Year in Review]]></title>
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2020/03/2019-year-in-review/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/12/2018-year-in-review/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2018 - Year in Review" />
            
                <id>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2020/03/2019-year-in-review/</id>
            
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Yash Agarwal</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2020-03-31T11:39:47+05:30</published>
            <updated>2020-03-31T11:39:47+05:30</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been three months since 2020 started. I was not able to keep up with my yearly habit of posting year reviews due to some reasons. One primary reason behind my negligence is my disinterest in writing on this blog. I felt that it was because the old layout of this blog had been too recurrent for me. So, I decided to fix that issue before thinking about writing.</p>
<p>The year 2019 was not a great year for me on many fronts. It was a year that reminded me of my limitations and brought me out of the bubble, that self-help books created for me. In retrospection, I find that I started a lot of things, with the intention of learning, but couldn&rsquo;t achieve any of the targets.</p>
<p>Like, I structure these posts every year, I have divided this post too in many sections. It makes it easier for me to focus on various aspects of my life in the past year. I will start with the best parts of my life.</p>
<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<p>I had decided to read 26 books in the year. I finished the year with 28 books. Out of 12 months, I did not read any book in January, November, and December. I finished two of the fiction series that I wanted to read for years - Harry Potter, and Percy Jackson. These two books are the reasons that I was able to finish 28 books in 9 months. It took me very little time to finish these book series. Other books (mostly non-fiction) took me ages to complete.</p>
<p>I am not sure if I am getting any value out of non-fiction books <em>right now</em>. I do not take notes and forget most of the lessons in a few days. Not sure if this is the right strategy while reading such books. Hence I have decided that I will reduce the number of non-fiction books <em>for some time</em> and put more attention to technical publications and CS books.</p>
<p>Though I am confident that my note-taking skills will not help in reading technical books either, I do hope to improve over time.</p>
<p>One of my reading goals from last year was to read a research paper every 15 days. I succeeded in the first quarter of the year and failed miserably after that. I started with a good intention and kept reading for some months. Then self-doubts began popping out. <em>What value am I getting out of this?</em>, was the question in my mind. I started this exercise because I have specific goals in my mind, and I wanted to improve myself academically. But when you are not able to answer such a question even to yourself, then something is wrong.</p>
<p>This failure has taught me some crucial lessons. I tend to start things without thinking about the end goal. It is the right approach when <em>learnings</em> from the process is more important than the result. But I was not able to focus on either of them. I lost my focus when I realized this.</p>
<p>I have come to understand the value of proper note-taking. I have read so many good books, but I do not remember any lessons from these books, because -</p>
<ul>
<li>I read passively and try to finish the book as quickly as possible.</li>
<li>I did not try to implement the lessons in my day to day life while reading.</li>
</ul>
<p>I lost my interest in reading news and blog articles also. I lost my interest from social media and, in general, the Internet entirely. I preferred to sleep as much as possible. That has its side-effects. Read on.</p>
<h2 id="blogging-and-writing">Blogging and Writing</h2>
<p>I had decided to write regularly in 2019. I didn&rsquo;t. It seems that failing was a norm for me in 2019. This section was my worst hit interest in 2019. Somehow, I was not able to gather the concentration required for writing. I used to get sudden motivations for a few days, I wrote during those periods. The rest of the time, I just thought that I should write. I think I suffered from the so-called <em>Writer&rsquo;s Block</em>.</p>
<h2 id="health">Health</h2>
<p>My analysis says that all my failures last year can be traced to this section. I was sick for almost a quarter of the year. Repeatedly getting ill and the time required for recovery took a toll on my body and mind. I lost all my focus and will power to do anything.</p>
<p>The exercise was again an issue. I certainly put more effort than last year, but that effort was scattered throughout the year, for small periods. So, I do not notice much difference. However, I continued to walk whenever I got time.</p>
<h2 id="work">Work</h2>
<p>It was not a very exciting year on the work front. I continued to work in Cisco this year. The work was neither very interesting nor very dull. The nature of my job is such that the exciting work shows up from time to time. With no fixed deadlines and no fixed way of doing things, it can be quite satisfying and quite frustrating at times.</p>
<h2 id="social-media">Social Media</h2>
<p>I lost my interest in social media altogether. I opened Facebook only to see the notification once in a while, sometimes after months. I got disillusioned by Twitter this year, because of the toxic political content there. I was never a regular user of YouTube anyway, so that was never a concern. However, I went to great lengths to delete every Google app from my phone, especially Gmail and YouTube. The email had become a new Facebook for me. I was checking emails every 15 minutes. So I signed out of Google account in my primary browser and restricted my email activities to a secondary browser. It helped me in keeping the urge to check email in control.</p>
<p>But this sudden disinterest has created a void in my typical day, which is quite reasonable given how much my life depends on the Internet. I am yet to figure out how to fill this void. Reading books did not help, however sleeping and watching movies helped for sure (however, not without its own set of problems).</p>
<h2 id="travel">Travel</h2>
<p>I was somewhat dissatisfied with myself for not traveling enough. This year, I had decided to travel extensively. But my health betrayed me. Out of 365 days, I was able to take the time of 4 days for travel. I went to Coorg and Chikmagalur with friends. Both trips happened during the wrong weather conditions. But the circumstances were such that I could not deny to my friends.</p>
<h2 id="miscellaneous">Miscellaneous</h2>
<p>My daily routine, more or less, remained the same. Though I couldn&rsquo;t wake up early in the morning most of the time, the reality is that I was not trying. My only intention behind waking up early in the morning was to meditate. I did that, however sporadically.</p>
<p>One other goal in 2019 was to get rid of procrastination. I did not care about it at all. Somehow, I was too busy fixing other issues in my life, that this seemed like a minor problem. Anyway, I did not attempt to do anything on a personal level, where procrastination would affect me. On the work front, at one point or another, you have to work and show results. So there it was never apparent. I tried many things to reduce the impact and influence of <em>technology</em> in my life. Although I consider myself successful to an extent, there is still scope for improvement.</p>
<p>In 2018, I was in full praise for to-do lists and the concept of maintaining goals. 2019 has busted all those praises. This year, these techniques did not work for me at all. Anyway, 2019 was one of those times when nothing worked for me, so this failure does not come as a surprise to me. Though, I still believe that this is something that can genuinely help me with some of my issues.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>If I had written this post at the beginning of the year 2020, I would have written some wish for the year 2020 at this place, as I always do, but this time is so gloomy that I am not able to think of anything good. I just pray to God that everything gets all right soon.</em></p>
<p><em>Being with family during this time, has given me some mental stability. But, it is also true that facing such circumstances and coming out triumphant, is what shows the human character.</em></p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups" term="write-ups" label="Write-ups" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/review" term="review" label="Review" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[2018 - Year in Review]]></title>
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/12/2018-year-in-review/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
            
                <id>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/12/2018-year-in-review/</id>
            
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Yash Agarwal</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2018-12-31T22:02:08+05:30</published>
            <updated>2018-12-31T22:02:08+05:30</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The year 2018 has been quite a roller coaster year for me. I saw many ups and downs, many successes, and many failures faced many
challenges on the personal front and struggled to keep myself on track. I have been working hard on improving my lifestyle
(not materialistically) for the last few years, and the benefits have begun to show up now. This year was a pinnacle in
that aspect. A lot of micro changes happened in my life this year.</p>
<p>I often read my blog posts from last year. Reading these posts give me a good feeling about
the improvements that I could bring in myself during the previous three years. Writing year <a href="/posts/2017/12/2017-the-best-till-now/">reviews</a> and posts like <a href="/posts/2018/08/beginning-a-new-journey/">this</a>,
<a href="/posts/2018/06/mistakes-that-i-made-in-nitc/">this</a> and <a href="/posts/2018/03/deactivated-my-facebook-account/">this</a> serve
as documents of my deeds from past for my future. It helps me in not repeating the same mistakes. As a human being, I
cannot run away from committing mistakes, but I can always make sure that I do not repeat the same mistakes.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Those who cannot remember the past are condemned to repeat it.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="blogging--writing">Blogging &amp; Writing</h2>
<p>I had set a target to write 15 blog articles at the beginning of this year. In the end, I managed to achieve this goal.
I managed to write 17 blog posts and six book reviews. My blog managed to get much traffic this year, mainly thanks to some of my technical posts.</p>
<p>I got some good responses from people about my technical blog posts. My aim to start writing technical posts was to keep an account
of what I learn. It feels very nice when I go back to my posts to read how I did something last time. So I consider
myself successful that at least I could benefit from my writing.</p>
<p>Though, in 2018, after leaving college, the frequency
of technical posts on this blog has dipped to almost zero. It is probably because I am not exploring enough after
joining the corporate world. In
college, I used Linux all the time, but now it is nearly four months since I last booted Linux in my system. I think it
is yet another phase of my learning, and I will take some time adjusting with this. I have some <em>lovely</em> technical post ideas, and I hope that I will be able to articulate them soon next year.</p>
<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<p>For most of the year, I did not pay any heed to books, and I was never very interested in buying
books. However, at the end of October, I purchased a Kindle Paperwhite. I
consider this to be the <a href="https://twitter.com/yash__here/status/1075396841267752963">best</a> investment done by me this year. Since buying it, I have read eight books. I finally managed to
finish my <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/10979019">Goodreads reading challenge</a> of 10 books. Although I
could not finish one book and included one <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/31284204-the-millionaire-booklet">audiobook</a> to this challenge to complete my target on time.</p>
<p>This year, I discovered my interest in Economics. I am reading some economics-related literature lately. It is a subtle shift
from my all-CS life. I plan to read a lot of economics-related books in 2019 to gain more expertise in this domain. But
I still need to figure out a way to stop it from interfering with my first (or second, maybe!) love.</p>
<p>Some of my favorite reads from this year (not in any particular order) -</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Technology / CS</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://danluu.com/branch-prediction/">Branch Prediction</a></li>
<li><a href="http://infolab.stanford.edu/~backrub/google.html">The Anatomy of a Large-Scale Hypertextual Web Search Engine</a></li>
<li><a href="https://chrisdown.name/2018/01/02/in-defence-of-swap.html">In defence of swap: common misconceptions</a></li>
<li><a href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2018/03/05/things-ive-learned-networking/">A few things I&rsquo;ve learned about computer networking</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/using-go-as-a-scripting-language-in-linux/">Using Go as a scripting language in Linux</a></li>
<li><a href="https://rcoh.me/posts/cache-oblivious-datastructures/">Maximize Cache Performance with this One Weird Trick: An Introduction to Cache-Oblivious Data
Structures</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/~mgk25/mswish/ut-rtc.html">IBM PC Real Time Clock should run in UT</a></li>
<li><a href="http://c-faq.com/decl/spiral.anderson.html">The ``Clockwise/Spiral Rule&rsquo;'</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nvie.com/posts/a-successful-git-branching-model/">A successful Git branching model</a></li>
<li><a href="http://mattjolson.github.io/2017/12/07/benefits-of-a-classical-education.html">So, should you do a CS degree?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/articles/accidentally_turing_complete.html">Accidentally Turing-Complete</a></li>
</ol>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<ol start="13">
<li><a href="https://www.xda-developers.com/apple-new-iphone-xr-influence-android-trends">How Apple’s New Lineup and iPhone XR will Influence Android Trends, for Better and
Worse</a></li>
<li><a href="https://scotthelme.co.uk/perfect-forward-secrecy/">Perfect Forward Secrecy - An Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blogs.dropbox.com/tech/2012/04/zxcvbn-realistic-password-strength-estimation/">zxcvbn: realistic password strength
estimation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://askubuntu.com/q/638382">How can I turn photos of paper documents into a scanned document?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/swlh/chatbots-were-the-next-big-thing-what-happened-5fc49dd6fa61">Chatbots were the next big thing: what
happened?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/07/the-ai-revolution-has-spawned-a-new-chips-arms-race/">The AI revolution has spawned a new chips arms
race</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/6/13/17446660/mozilla-firefox-pocket-recommendations-ceo-nate-weiner-interview-converge-podcast">How Firefox is using Pocket to try to build a better news feed than
Facebook</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.diamandis.com/blog/countdown-to-the-singularity">Countdown to the Singularity</a></li>
<li><a href="https://qz.com/1366350/what-the-hell-is-going-on-with-apple/">What the hell is going on with Apple?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://interestingengineering.com/why-chinese-artificial-intelligence-will-run-the-world">Why Chinese Artificial Intelligence Will Run The
World</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/s/612327/europes-quest-for-an-unhackable-quantum-internet/">Inside Europe’s quest to build an unhackable quantum internet</a></li>
<li><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/computing/hardware/the-case-against-quantum-computing">The Case Against Quantum
Computing</a></li>
</ol>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Economics</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/why-hard-escape-amazons-long-reach/">Why It&rsquo;s Hard to Escape Amazon&rsquo;s Long Reach</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.aboveavalon.com/notes/2018/7/11/the-race-to-a-trillion">The Race to a Trillion</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bloombergquint.com/opinion/ambani-is-ready-for-his-triple-play-close-up">Ambani Is Ready for His Triple Play Close-Up</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.livemint.com/Opinion/M0oJYwIP1OxJWnzaz6Eo8H/Penalty-kicks-and-behavioural-economics.html">Penalty kicks and behavioural
economics</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/the-psychology-of-money/">The Psychology of Money</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2018-apple-trillion-dollar-world/">Apple’s Trillion-Dollar World</a></li>
<li><a href="https://hbr.org/2018/08/how-to-beat-mid-career-malaise">How to Beat Mid-Career Malaise</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2018/jul/10/the-staggering-rise-of-indias-super-rich">The staggering rise of India’s
super-rich</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2018/08/the-problem-with-bezos-billions/566552/">Jeff Bezos’s $150 Billion Fortune Is a Policy
Failure</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2018/08/06/how-year-old-roads-predict-modern-day-prosperity">How 2,000-year-old roads predict modern-day prosperity</a></li>
<li><a href="https://25iq.com/2018/08/11/how-subscription-business-models-are-changing-business-and-investing-the-microeconomics-of-subscriptions/">How Subscription Business Models are Changing Business and Investing (the Microeconomics of
Subscriptions)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.getrichslowly.org/income-vs-wealth/">What it means to be rich: The difference between income and
wealth</a></li>
<li><a href="https://seekingalpha.com/article/4205122-dark-decade-ahead">The Dark Decade Ahead</a></li>
<li><a href="https://stratechery.com/2018/the-iphone-franchise/">The iPhone Franchise</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/09/17/the-real-cost-of-the-2008-financial-crisis">The Real Cost of the 2008 Financial
Crisis</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/naval/status/1002103360646823936?lang=en">How to Get Rich (without getting lucky)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://zandercutt.com/2018/08/23/the-approval-economy/">The Approval Economy</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/outlook/five-myths/five-myths-about-capitalism/2018/09/27/3f0b72f6-c06f-11e8-90c9-23f963eea204_story.html">Five myths about
capitalism</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/23/17970466/amazon-prime-shopping-behavior-streaming-alexa-minimum-wage">How Amazon’s Retail Revolution Is Changing The Way We Shop</a></li>
<li><a href="http://evonomics.com/wealth-power-productivity-laurie-macfarlane/">Why Wealth Is Determined More by Power Than
Productivity</a></li>
<li><a href="https://justinjackson.ca/costs">Let&rsquo;s Talk About Startup Costs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2018-11-16/how-companies-get-you-to-pay-more-for-the-same-product">How Companies Get You to Pay More for the Same
Product</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2018/10/31/18048340/art-market-expensive-ai-painting">Why is art so expensive?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/12/18/business/bond-market-risks.html">Stock Markets Are Wild, but Bond Markets Can Be Dangerous</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.livemint.com/Companies/HNZA71LNVNNVXQ1eaIKu6M/British-Raj-siphoned-out-45-trillion-from-India-Utsa-Patna.html">British Raj siphoned out $45 trillion from India: Utsa
Patnaik</a></li>
<li><a href="https://theweek.com/articles/809324/how-spot-next-recession">How to spot the next recession</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<ul>
<li><strong>Misc</strong>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/21/technology/personaltech/smart-things-dumb-stuff.html">In an Era of ‘Smart’ Things, Sometimes Dumb Stuff Is
Better</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.theladders.com/career-advice/einstein-aristotle-and-ockham-on-how-real-geniuses-solve-difficult-problems">Einstein, Aristotle, and Ockham on how real geniuses solve difficult problems</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.theglobeandmail.com/technology/your-smartphone-is-making-you-stupid/article37511900/">Your smartphone📱is making you👈 stupid, antisocial 🙅 and unhealthy 😷. So why can&rsquo;t you put it
down❔⁉️</a></li>
<li>Indian Nationalism: The Memories Of History – <a href="https://swarajyamag.com/ideas/indian-nationalism-the-memories-of-history-part-i">Part
I</a>, <a href="https://swarajyamag.com/ideas/indian-nationalism-nehruvian-and-marxist-conception-of-india-part-ii">Part
II</a>, <a href="https://swarajyamag.com/ideas/indian-nationalism-the-nationalist-conception-of-india-part-iii">Part
III</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.ncase.me/take-your-time/">Take Your Time</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/02/28/magazine/what-google-learned-from-its-quest-to-build-the-perfect-team.html">What Google Learned From Its Quest to Build the Perfect Team</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/12/10/the-friendship-that-made-google-huge">The Friendship That Made Google Huge</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/you-what-write-harry-shum/">You are what you write</a></li>
<li><a href="https://swarajyamag.com/ideas/being-dk-in-the-age-of-msd">Being DK In The Age Of MSD</a></li>
<li><a href="https://scroll.in/field/868038/post-retirement-rahul-dravid-is-now-getting-the-unconditional-love-he-always-deserved-as-under-19-world-cup-triumph-showed">The growing legacy of Rahul Sharad Dravid</a></li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/@ztrana/the-only-real-way-to-acquire-wisdom-7489a10c8f8e">The Only Real Way to Acquire Wisdom</a></li>
<li><a href="https://praxis.fortelabs.co/personal-sprints-applying-design-thinking-to-your-life/">Personal Sprints: Applying Design Thinking to Your Life</a></li>
<li><a href="https://fs.blog/2018/06/succeed-at-work/">Smarter, Not Harder: How to Succeed at Work</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/real-life-schrodingers-cats-probe-the-boundary-of-the-quantum-world-20180625/">Real-Life Schrödinger’s Cats Probe the Boundary of the Quantum World</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2018/06/15/which-traits-predict-graduates-earnings">Which traits predict graduates’ earnings?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://andrewchen.co/power-user-curve/">The Power User Curve: The best way to understand your most engaged users</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.economist.com/the-world-if/2018/07/07/what-if-people-were-paid-for-their-data">What if people were paid for their data?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/graduate-student-solves-quantum-verification-problem-20181008/">Graduate Student Solves Quantum Verification Problem</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.spectator.co.uk/2018/07/it-doesnt-matter-how-hard-you-work-just-how-busy-you-look/">It doesn’t matter how hard you work – just how busy you look</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/love.html">How to Do What You Love</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/08/14/style/how-can-i-focus-better.html">Finding It Hard to Focus? Maybe It’s Not Your Fault</a></li>
<li><a href="https://avc.com/2018/08/first-mover-disadvantage/">First Mover Disadvantage</a></li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/@gettinadmin/the-sharechat-phenomenon-6dfff8244af1">The ShareChat Phenomenon</a></li>
<li><a href="https://scroll.in/article/890631/vinod-mehta-on-atal-behari-vajpayee-and-the-1998-nuclear-tests-how-a-tired-pm-became-a-bold-pm">Atal Bihari Vajpayee and his Achilles heel: Excerpts from Vinod Mehta’s memoirs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://qz.com/work/1373353/work-life-balance-is-an-unhealthy-myth/">Work-life balance is an unhealthy myth</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018/09/04/who-controls-your-data/">Who controls your data?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/your-first-ninety-days-in-hell">Your First Ninety Days in Hell</a></li>
<li><a href="https://qz.com/1422925/the-public-internet-was-almost-a-democracy/">The internet can’t handle functioning like a democracy</a></li>
<li><a href="https://waitbutwhy.com/2018/04/picking-career.html">How to Pick a Career (That Actually Fits You)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://fs.blog/2018/10/long-game/">The Surprising Power of The Long Game</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.jotform.com/blog/the-world-needs-polymaths/">Why the world needs deep generalists, not specialists</a></li>
<li><a href="https://waitbutwhy.com/2014/12/10-types-odd-friendships-youre-probably-part.html">10 Types of Odd Friendships You’re Probably Part Of</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I used <a href="https://www.instapaper.com">Instapaper</a> extensively throughout the year to manage and save the articles that I liked. Although I was never
very consistent in reading those saved articles, it was still a good exercise. I finished all my pending pile of
saved articles by the end of the year. Moreover, for this post, it became straightforward for me to recollect those
links. This list grew excessively large, but I did not want to lose any of these links because of some random third-party
service shutting down, so I am adding them here for easy reference in the future.</p>
<p>Next year onwards, I plan to read one academic paper from my favorite areas of CS in every two weeks and summarise them to improve my
understanding of the domain (the <a href="/readings">readings</a> section of my blog was initially intended for this purpose). Moreover, seeing my experience in the last two months, I feel encouraged to increase my Goodreads
reading challenge to 20 books.</p>
<h2 id="work">Work</h2>
<p>The year 2018 was a pivotal year for me on this front. It was the year when I had to come out of the comfort zone of my
parents&rsquo; protection. My professional life began this year, and I started earning MONEY. It feels delightful when you see the money gets deposited to your bank account every month for the hard(!) work that you
have done for the last one month. But</p>
<blockquote>
<p>With great power comes great responsibility.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I believe that I have been able to control this feeling of power quite nicely until now. Probably being an <em>Agarwal</em> helped :P</p>
<p>Coming back to work, those who do not know, I joined Cisco Systems this year as a Software Engineer. The job is pretty good for my initial expectations. I made some good friends. First time in my life, I managed to make a group of friends.</p>
<p>Quite an achievement.</p>
<h2 id="studies">Studies</h2>
<p>This year was officially my last year in formal education. <!-- raw HTML omitted --> Although I failed to finish my bachelors with a satisfactory final GPA (at least I am not happy with it), I am very much satisfied with all my learnings from college. I learned many life lessons, kept myself in
check, built some useful contacts, learned a lot about many CS-related things, and ended up with a decent job in the
end.</p>
<p>However, I sense that this is not the happy ending of my journey towards learning, and I have a lot more to learn. I
recently read the book &ldquo;The Alchemist,&rdquo; and the central theme of this book is to keep looking for your legend. I am
still searching for my legend. In 2019, I expect to find new ways to keep learning and explore new areas both in CS and other fields of life.</p>
<h2 id="relationships">Relationships</h2>
<p>Before this year, I had an assumption that I lack social skills. I hesitated in talking to people. I decided to change
it this year. I was waiting for a change in my life, probably because NITC had become too monotonous for me. It was one of my
new year&rsquo;s resolution that I will change myself and become more approachable to people.</p>
<p>I do not know if I have changed or not, but I feel much more confident now than ever in communicating with people. I hope I will continue to improve in 2019 as well.</p>
<h2 id="social-media">Social Media</h2>
<p>I was trying to get rid of Facebook for quite some time. This year, I finally managed to control my addiction. For a
good part of the year, either my Facebook account remained deactivated, or I was logged out of it. In the past, I used to feel a
strong urge to open Facebook every ten minutes, but this year, I was able to keep this urge in control. When my account was not
deactivated, I kept myself so busy in other works, that I did not even think of Facebook.</p>
<p>Moreover, the good thing is that I
did not notice any symptoms of withdrawal symptoms because of this sudden quitting of Facebook. A friend&rsquo;s advice worked
nicely. It was quite tricky, indeed.</p>
<p>I was never addicted to any other social media platform, but I decided that I can use Twitter for my benefit. I feel
Twitter is a useful tool if utilized correctly. I followed many people who tweet regularly about CS related stuff. I open
Twitter once every 2-3 days for a very short duration to collect some articles and tips. Nowadays, these articles, along with a few blog articles from Feedly, mainly form my Instapaper feed. Though Instapaper recently switched to
commercial model again, I decided to keep using it for the time being until I find some other alternative.</p>
<h2 id="miscellaneous">Miscellaneous</h2>
<p>I had decided to exercise for at least 90% part of 2018. I failed miserably. Leave alone every day; I could not even do it
continuously for one month. I need to make this a top priority. Otherwise, it is going to create trouble for me soon.</p>
<p>For the last two years, I am trying to get up early in the morning every day. My body does not seem to care, though. It seems a classic
example of the struggle between mind and body. My brain says that I am an early bird, but my body straightforwardly rejects
this idea. I have felt the positives of waking up early, so I am still trying my best so that my body can
adjust to this change. I will keep working on this habit in 2019 as well.</p>
<p>I noticed a bad habit in myself - procrastination. I procrastinated a lot in 2018. Things that I could have finished well
within the deadlines took me ages to complete. I was always late in my BTech project deadlines, I could not finish one of my
hobby projects, I could not finish my study targets on time, and many other such examples haunted me this year. It is one
of my most important goals of 2019 that I need a way to find how to concentrate on one thing at a time. Many things distract me while I am working. Technology itself is a significant distraction, but because I am a CS
professional, this is one thing from which I cannot run away. However, I will still try to avoid getting distracted
by my <em>curiosity</em> and put more focus on doing work.</p>
<p>I am writing more than ever. However, with my increased writing, my English vocabulary is not enough anymore. This year, it
happened many times that I wanted to write something, but because of the lack of proper words in my vocabulary, I had to
settle with <em>inferior</em> words. I tried multiple times this year to work on improving my vocabulary, but I failed badly.
I will increase my focus on improving my knowledge of English in 2019 so that such small issues do not stop me from adding something to my skills.</p>
<p>This year, I experimented and tried to organize myself with to-do lists. It was a fruitful exercise, and it had a lot of sound effects on my productivity. The days when I made a to-do list, I felt very energetic and encouraged to
finish all the tasks on my list. However, then I noticed one thing, I could not continue doing this for more than a few days at
once. For initial days, I felt encouraged to complete my tasks, but soon it began to appear as a
burden, and I felt exhausted. So it seems that something in the middle will work for me. This year, I will continue
using to-do lists (I use Google Keep for this) but for short durations of time. I will refrain from using it every day
to avoid getting exhausted. I am considering a switch to <a href="https://www.notion.so">Notion</a> to maintain my monthly and long-term goals.
Probably that will also help me in keeping track of my goals without feeling the heat.</p>
<p>All of my friends love to travel. It seems a common habit in most of my friends. However, I am an exception. I&rsquo;m not particularly eager to go on trips. I attribute it to my issues with motion sickness. For the whole year of 2018, I do not have a single
trip memory other than my travels to Bengaluru and Jaipur airports. Oh yeah, after thinking for some time, I recalled that I went on one trip
from Bengaluru to Calicut to attend my convocation ceremony. That&rsquo;s all! I will <em>consider</em> accepting trip invitations
from my friends in 2019. Up until now, I keep refusing to join them in their trips due to my health issues, my desire to
stay in solitude and partially because of my unwillingness to explore anything outside technology. However, it is time I start changing
myself.</p>
<p>It was a grave mistake that during my four-year stay in Kerala, I did not try to learn Malayalam. I feel that I
missed an excellent opportunity to learn a new language. Although I am as bad as other north Indians when it comes to
knowing multiple languages (correct me if I am wrong, I do not intend to generalize all north Indians), I think that learning a new language can be very beneficial for <em>some parts of my brain</em>. Now I am in Karnataka, yet
another south Indian state and with yet another language. It is an excellent opportunity, and I am not going to repeat
my mistake this time. Even if I do not succeed in learning Kannada, it will provide enough challenges to my brain for the short term.
Who knows, it might also give me a new skill!</p>
<p><strong>Welcome 2019, I hope that you will help me in taking a step closer to discovering myself. Give me new experiences, keep me grounded and help me in
contributing to the progress of my India.</strong> 😊</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups" term="write-ups" label="Write-ups" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/review" term="review" label="Review" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beginning a New Journey]]></title>
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/08/beginning-a-new-journey/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
            
                <id>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/08/beginning-a-new-journey/</id>
            
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Yash Agarwal</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2018-08-25T21:16:41+05:30</published>
            <updated>2018-08-25T21:16:41+05:30</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I was in eighth (or was it ninth?) class, one of our teachers asked in the class, what do you want to become in your life? People said a lot of things. When my turn came up, I stood up and said, <em>“Mein software engineer banana chahta hu”</em> (I want to become a software engineer). It was not that I was genuinely interested in Computers. When I look back now, I realize that it was my cousins who affected my choice (in an indirect way), and their achievements fascinated me to aim at this particular career choice.</p>
<p>My whole life for the last seven years was revolving around this one dream(!) of getting a job in an MNC. I got my chance when I got placed in Cisco last Monsoon. I was super excited about joining Cisco since then. Perhaps because of the MacBook on which I am typing this article right now 😄 and partly because of the monotonicity of the NIT-C environment. I wanted to break out of the comfort zone that I had built there around myself in NIT-C. Changing place seemed the only viable option.</p>
<p>I have been doing a self-introspection for the last four to five months. My blog posts from the previous few months reflect some hints about my introspections. I have mentioned my observations here and there in a few of my blog posts. I discovered some unique aspects of my personality. On the other hand, I found out some traits which are pretty weird (in my opinion :) ). I am not going to publish all of my findings, but one thing became apparent, my social anxiety requires my immediate attention.</p>
<p>It is quite difficult to change some aspects of our personality; usually those we are born with. But most of the qualities that define someone keeps changing. Life experiences play an essential role in determining a person’s character. Success and failure define a person. I firmly believe that no person ever remains the same. People continuously go through phases of realizations and the ups and downs in the career, academics, broken trusts, dampening creativity, growing age, success, glory, hatred, and betrayals. People become what they are because of the world around them. These realizations come from experiences and experiences that come from bad experiences.</p>
<p>I learned this the hard way!</p>
<p>So, I decided, I will not commit those similar set of mistakes again. I will make new mistakes 😜. I realized that there exists a world outside computers and tech. I need to go and talk to people. If not random strangers, I should talk to my friends, take part in various activities, play some sport, focus on my fitness and mental health, and go on trips. And of course, perform well in work and maintain a good work-life balance if it is not a <a href="https://theascent.pub/is-work-life-balance-a-myth-c328377966de">myth</a>.</p>
<p>I cannot change the past now. It is only the future that is yet in my power. I am eager to see how my current actions are going to affect my future.</p>
<p>At last, let me finish this article by quoting Winston Churchill (Although I am not a big fan of him, this quote is worth sharing).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If we open a quarrel between past and present, we shall find that we have lost the future.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Cheers. 😄</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups" term="write-ups" label="Write-ups" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Good and Bad about CSED of NIT-C]]></title>
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/the-good-and-bad-about-csed-of-nit-c/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/mistakes-that-i-made-in-nitc/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Mistakes That I Made in NITC" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/searching-the-goal/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Searching the goal" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/so-i-applied-for-gsoc/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="So I Applied for GSoC" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/fossmeet18/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="FOSSMeet&#39;18" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/deactivated-my-facebook-account/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Deactivated My Facebook Account" />
            
                <id>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/the-good-and-bad-about-csed-of-nit-c/</id>
            
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Yash Agarwal</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2018-06-14T17:59:28+05:30</published>
            <updated>2018-06-14T17:59:28+05:30</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Four years ago, in this very month of June, JEE Mains results were out. I had screwed up my JEE Advanced, so I had to settle for an NIT. My AIR was good enough to get me a seat of Computer Science and Engineering in any of the NITs except the first three (at that time Trichy, Warangal, and Surathkal). I was skeptical about going to <a href="http://nitc.ac.in/">NIT Calicut</a> because of its distance from my native place, so NIT Allahabad was the most suitable choice. However, in the end, I decided to give preference to NIT Calicut over NIT Allahabad. One of the many reasons for this decision was an excellent <a href="http://dsanghi.blogspot.com/2011/05/my-2011-list-of-recommended-csit.html">article</a> by Dr. Dheeraj Sanghi, a retired professor from IIT Kanpur. His blog post was the primary reason; I decided to go with NIT Calicut. Now that I have graduated from NIT Calicut, I think it is the right time to document my observations about the CSE department of NIT Calicut from the perspective of a student.</p>
<p>My exposure to the CSE department was limited to the facilities provided to undergraduate students only (almost everything except some academic facilities), so I am not entirely sure if this article will help any of the postgraduate students out there. However, some points below might help you decide about the non-academic activities of the department.</p>
<h2 id="faculties">Faculties</h2>
<p>Like every other NIT, NIT Calicut also suffers from the lack of permanent faculties. Most of the faculties in the department are recruited on a contract basis (ad-hoc). It is <strong>not</strong> necessarily a <a href="http://dsanghi.blogspot.com/2018/05/teaching-by-temps-it-is-budget-issue-too.html">bad</a> thing, but many a time, an ad-hoc faculty gets to teach a subject where one does not hold strong command. In that case, the subject becomes a burden for both student and teacher. It happened to me many times when I was stuck in a situation that I ended up losing my interest in the subject as well as grades.</p>
<p>Most of the core subjects are taught by permanent faculties who are very good at their subjects. These faculties are very experienced and are alumni of some of India&rsquo;s top IITs and IISc. The department used to <a href="http://dsanghi.blogspot.com/2011/05/my-2011-list-of-recommended-csit.html">ask</a> new hires to get a postgraduate degree from some IIT or IISc, but this does not seem to be the case anymore.</p>
<p>Most of the professors prefer to teach traditional computer science subjects, so if you are interested in AI, Data Science, or any other such areas of computer science, then you might have to depend on self-study.</p>
<h2 id="club-activities">Club Activities</h2>
<p><a href="http://assoc.cse.nitc.ac.in">CSEA</a> is the main departmental club that organizes almost every co-curricular activity in the department. In my opinion, CSEA is the best department association in NIT Calicut. I was not a member of CSEA, so all of my views are from the perspective of an outsider. CSEA organizes talks and workshops for the freshers from time to time. I attended all the lectures and seminars arranged by CSEA in my initial years, and I feel that those workshops were quite beneficial for me as a student.</p>
<p>FOSSCell is a group of students who contribute to open-source software. FOSSCell organizes workshops related to Linux and open source contributions. It also organizes <a href="http://fossmeet.in/">FOSSMeet</a>, the yearly free and open-source software conference organized in NIT-C. It is one of the largest gatherings of open source enthusiasts in South India. I have written two posts about my experience as a part of the organizing team of FOSSMeet. You can read them <a href="/posts/2017/03/fossmeet17/">here</a> and <a href="/posts/2018/03/fossmeet18/">here</a>. Attending and organizing FOSSMeet is one of the best experiences of my college life. The current executives of FOSSCell are actively working on improving the state of open source contributions in NIT-C. I hope the situation will change in the coming years.</p>
<p>The students manage all the labs in the department. The <a href="http://athena.nitc.ac.in">Software Systems Lab</a> is assigned to undergraduate students. This lab is probably the crown jewel and pride of every CS student of NIT Calicut. It remains open most of the time. All the department servers are kept in this lab and are managed independently by the student administrators chosen by the student administrators. The student administrators are given the responsibility to maintain all the department websites. I do not know if any other university or college in India provides such independence to its students. I was one of the student administrators in this lab, and I consider that this was the best thing that happened to me during my graduation.</p>
<h2 id="the-infrastructure">The Infrastructure</h2>
<p>A traditional computer science course does not require many types of equipment except a laptop and a fast enough internet connection. Internet speed is not extraordinary in NIT-C, but it was sufficient for me. The network administrators blocked many websites, but if the site is related to coursework, sending a short mail was enough in most cases to get it unblocked.</p>
<p>The labs are equipped with modern computer systems, and Ubuntu is installed on almost every department system. The particular emphasis on the use of open-source software is a big plus point for the department.</p>
<h2 id="courses">Courses</h2>
<p>The curriculum was last updated in 2010. Since then, six batches have graduated. I think it is an excellent time to consider revising it. The current curriculum is good enough for most traditional CS subjects, but its focus on the present buzzwords of the CS world is very less. I heard that the department changed the curriculum for the batches joining 2017 onwards, but I doubt that there are any significant changes.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>The academics are taken quite seriously in the department (apparently). The level of question papers in examinations is generally very tough. I always felt the heat, at least. However, teachers are quite friendly and will help you with any of your queries.</p>
<p>The situation of lab courses (except OS, Compilers, and DSA lab) in the department is very pathetic. Operating Systems lab and Compiler lab have a well-defined structure, and the feeling of developing your tiny OS or compiler is one of the best feelings ever. Data Structure and Algorithms lab runs in parallel to the corresponding theory course, and that helps students in understanding theory by practice.</p>
<p>I cannot say the same about any other lab in the department; most of the students end up learning nothing new from these lab courses. The problem is in the way these courses are handled. There does not seem to be a proper structure of teaching in these courses. Students are expected to learn on their own and come to the lab and give exams. Although most of the time, the corresponding theory course carries marks for a mini project which compensates for the lab course, these lab courses do have some scope for improvements.</p>
<h2 id="placements--higher-studies">Placements &amp; Higher Studies</h2>
<p>The department does not handle placements, but the quality of education and the focus on industry-oriented courses do affect the placements. The placement department of NIT-C has been doing an excellent job of maintaining a track record of over 90% placements from computer science every year.</p>
<p>Department, as such, does not focus on placements much. I feel that the department is more interested in making researchers than software engineers. Most of the courses are very heavily inclined towards theory. From my batch, I know at least ten people who are planning to go to the USA for higher studies in the next two years. The faculties also encourage students to pursue higher education (and subsequently research). Perhaps, it is one of the reasons that the state of competitive coding is not very good in the department.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Despite continuous lack of good permanent faculties and its location disadvantages, CSED of NIT-C has managed to produce competent engineers year by year. Spending four years in Kerala can be a different experience for outsiders, especially North Indians, but it is an experience worth gaining. If you have a good rank in JEE Mains and do not mind going too far from home, CSED of NIT Calicut is an excellent choice. I hope you will not regret the decision, though I will not say the same about other departments of NIT-C.</p>
<p>If you decide to join NIT-C, do read my article about my <a href="/posts/2018/06/mistakes-that-i-made-in-nitc/">experience</a> at NIT Calicut.</p>
<p>Thanks to my friends <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/aashishsatya">Aashish</a>, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahaveer-chouhan-575abba7/">Mahaveer</a> and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/faris.shajahan.1">Faris</a> for reading the drafts of this article and providing their suggestions.</p>
<p>Best wishes. Cheers 😄</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups" term="write-ups" label="Write-ups" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/cse" term="cse" label="CSE" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/review" term="review" label="review" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/nitc" term="nitc" label="NITC" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes That I Made in NITC]]></title>
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/mistakes-that-i-made-in-nitc/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/searching-the-goal/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Searching the goal" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/so-i-applied-for-gsoc/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="So I Applied for GSoC" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/fossmeet18/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="FOSSMeet&#39;18" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/deactivated-my-facebook-account/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Deactivated My Facebook Account" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/why-a-sanskrit-shloka/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Why a Sanskrit Shloka?" />
            
                <id>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/mistakes-that-i-made-in-nitc/</id>
            
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Yash Agarwal</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2018-06-01T10:21:45+05:30</published>
            <updated>2018-06-01T10:21:45+05:30</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now that I am graduated from NIT Calicut, one more chapter of my life is over. It is time to move on to the next page, but before I begin that phase, I thought it would be nice, to sum up, the experience that I gathered in NIT Calicut. The last four years have been great for me. I learned a lot of new life lessons, but there were some decisions that I could have avoided. I take full responsibility for my actions and do not blame anybody for the same. Although I do not regret taking any of those decisions, I feel it is crucial to document all those lessons before they vanish from my <em>otherwise</em> average memory. This post is intended to serve as a document for my future self, but most of the content here should be able to help anyone who happens to read this post. Most of this content has been taken from my journal, which I maintained (not consistently) over the last two years.</p>
<h2 id="studies">Studies</h2>
<p>From the first year itself, I had an impression from various online QA sites and some seniors that studies are not a big deal in college. That was a grave mistake which cost me a lot during my college life. I tried to compensate for it in the latter half of my graduation, but that was not enough.</p>
<p>While my friends used to learn by teaching each other, I never enjoyed studying in groups. I wish I had participated more in such group learning activities.</p>
<p>Most of the courses taught in traditional colleges like NITC are useless, in my opinion. However, Data Structures and Algorithms(DSA) was one subject which shows its importance again and again. It is one of those subjects where I should have put more attention. Although I was suffering from a fracture at the time of this course, some more efforts from my side could have changed things as they are today.</p>
<h2 id="wrong-learning-methods">Wrong learning methods</h2>
<p>I always tended to learn anything new using the tutorials available on the Internet. It is fine, but I never tried to do any projects/practicals to strengthen my learning. In my experience, it is always better to learn any programming language by doing projects in it.</p>
<p>My first programming language was C, which was taught in an introductory course in the first year. C is a relatively low-level language, and it helped me in understanding many concepts and working on many systems related stuff. Still, I feel that it is also one of the reasons that I am not able to think in higher-level abstraction. When I started learning Python, I was not able to think anything in abstract terms. I wish I had put more effort into learning Python or any other OOP language early in my college life.</p>
<h2 id="communication">Communication</h2>
<p>I have always been an introvert person when it comes to communicating with people. I wish I had worked on improving this aspect of my personality. For the first two years, I never asked any seniors for advice, never asked any questions in the classroom, never discussed project ideas with any faculty. I tried to improve myself in the last two years, and I feel satisfied with my efforts. In my opinion, it is always better to ask a more experienced person for their advice than to take blind steps and regret later.</p>
<p>I was hesitant about talking to people from different linguistic backgrounds in my first and second years. Again thanks to my inability to communicate with new people. I improved this later, but first impressions are crucial, if not everything.</p>
<h2 id="friends-and-seniors">Friends and seniors</h2>
<p>In my first year, I made a mistake by choosing to befriend some people who identified themselves as <em>state seniors</em> (people from the same north Indian state as I am). I was naive in identifying people at that time, but when I look back now, I feel that if I had avoided those people and invested that time in learning something related to CS, I could have gained more out of college. For a person who was entirely new for CS, that one year&rsquo;s time was very crucial, and I completely wasted it. It took me two years to rectify my mistake.</p>
<h2 id="not-taking-breaks">Not taking breaks</h2>
<p>I never took breaks from learning new things. I always put my work ahead of my personal life. That was the wrong approach. However, I do not blame myself for this. I was new to such work-life equations, and I did not realize the requirement to maintain a proper work-life balance. I wanted to learn a lot of new things, and college provided me a suitable environment, but I feel that I exhausted myself many times. That resulted in my loss of interest from Computer Science also in the second year.</p>
<h2 id="writing-and-reading">Writing and Reading</h2>
<p>I was never a voracious reader in my childhood. I never tried to spend my free time with books. After coming to college, I saw many people reading books day and night. That inspired me to develop a new hobby of <strong>Reading</strong>. Although I still do not read a lot (just 5-6 books a year), it is better than reading none.</p>
<p>I started this blog in the second year. My intention was <em>not</em> to write. I just wanted to learn how to set up Wordpress and Jekyll. However, slowly I developed the habit of writing. I now consider it the biggest takeaway from college. Writing a blog has helped me learn new things and systematically explain things.</p>
<p>I tried to write a journal to document significant events in life, but I could not maintain it regularly. That is one thing which I would like to improve in the coming years.</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups" term="write-ups" label="Write-ups" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/nitc" term="nitc" label="NITC" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/cse" term="cse" label="CSE" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[So I Applied for GSoC]]></title>
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/so-i-applied-for-gsoc/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/fossmeet18/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="FOSSMeet&#39;18" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/03/fossmeet17/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="FOSSMeet&#39;17" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/searching-the-goal/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Searching the goal" />
            
                <id>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/so-i-applied-for-gsoc/</id>
            
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Yash Agarwal</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2018-03-28T20:58:26+05:30</published>
            <updated>2018-03-28T20:58:26+05:30</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[



    

    
    

    
    <link rel="stylesheet" href="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/photoswipe/4.1.1/photoswipe.min.css" integrity="sha256-sCl5PUOGMLfFYctzDW3MtRib0ctyUvI9Qsmq2wXOeBY=" crossorigin="anonymous" />
    <link rel="stylesheet" href="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/photoswipe/4.1.1/default-skin/default-skin.min.css" integrity="sha256-BFeI1V+Vh1Rk37wswuOYn5lsTcaU96hGaI7OUVCLjPc=" crossorigin="anonymous" />

    
    <link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/photoswipe.min.d780348a887d97b4d6cc664301a2941706e4a02aeb1533524fcce3b7b9b64b4f.css">

    

    
    <div class="pswp" tabindex="-1" role="dialog" aria-hidden="true">
        
        <div class="pswp__bg"></div>
        
        <div class="pswp__scroll-wrap">
            
            <div class="pswp__container">
                <div class="pswp__item"></div>
                <div class="pswp__item"></div>
                <div class="pswp__item"></div>
            </div>
            
            <div class="pswp__ui pswp__ui--hidden">
                <div class="pswp__top-bar">
                    
                    <div class="pswp__counter"></div>
                    <button class="pswp__button pswp__button--close" title="Close (Esc)"></button>
                    <button class="pswp__button pswp__button--share" title="Share"></button>
                    <button class="pswp__button pswp__button--fs" title="Toggle fullscreen"></button>
                    <button class="pswp__button pswp__button--zoom" title="Zoom in/out"></button>
                    
                    
                    <div class="pswp__preloader">
                        <div class="pswp__preloader__icn">
                            <div class="pswp__preloader__cut">
                                <div class="pswp__preloader__donut"></div>
                            </div>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div class="pswp__share-modal pswp__share-modal--hidden pswp__single-tap">
                    <div class="pswp__share-tooltip"></div>
                </div>
                <button class="pswp__button pswp__button--arrow--left" title="Previous (arrow left)">
                </button>
                <button class="pswp__button pswp__button--arrow--right" title="Next (arrow right)">
                </button>
                <div class="pswp__caption">
                    <div class="pswp__caption__center"></div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

<p>I first heard about Google Summer of Code (GSoC) in my second year (2016). It was quite fascinating to know that such a program exists (possibly because of that super attractive amount of money, $5500 at that time). I researched about it and sent emails to some mentors. The replies were mostly encouraging, but I still could not gather the courage to apply as I used to doubt my capabilities. Then last year (2017) again, I decided that I should try for GSoC one more time. I looked for the projects, started reading codebase of one project, but due to my lack of determination, I again did not apply.</p>
<p>In the summers of 2017, I got some time to think about it. I decided that for the next year, I will try everything to make sure that I apply for GSoC 2018. I started coding as much as possible and pushing my code to GitHub to build an impressive profile.</p>
<p>Now I can say that I am satisfied with my efforts to some extent. I did start some good <a href="https://github.com/yashhere/BeautifyMP3">open</a> <a href="https://github.com/yashhere/ConMan">source</a> <a href="https://github.com/yashhere/Goofy">projects</a>. They are not very extraordinary, but something is better than nothing. I dived into Debian packaging also and volunteered for a FOSS event. Spreading awareness about FOSS is also contributing to FOSS. Isn&rsquo;t it?</p>
<p>Coming back to GSoC, this year, I have successfully submitted a proposal to the Debian Project. It does not matter whether I get it or not. I overcame one of my biggest fears of doubting my capabilities. It is something that I was trying to do for the last two years. This moment is worth celebrating.</p>
<p>Read about my GSoC project on <a href="https://wiki.debian.org/SummerOfCode2018/Projects#SummerOfCode2018.2FProjects.2FBootTorrent.Boot_many_machines_via_bittorrent">Boot Many Machines via Bittorrent</a>. It is related to something which I learned in <a href="http://athena.nitc.ac.in/">SSL</a> as SSL admin.</p>
<p>Read my project proposal on <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1N7wcc6rwFuauTS-jH2JuLDnZIX0w79AzTPSvSJU3PtA/edit?usp=sharing">Google Drive</a> or <a href="https://wiki.debian.org/YashAgarwal/GSoCProposal">Debian Wiki</a>.</p>



    <link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/hugo-easy-gallery.css">
    


<div class="box"  itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageGallery">
    <figure  itemprop="associatedMedia" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject">
        <div class="img">
            <img itemprop="thumbnail" src="/images/posts/2018-03-28/gsoc-timeline.png#center" alt="gsoc timeline"/>
        </div>
        <a href="/images/posts/2018-03-28/gsoc-timeline.png#center" itemprop="contentUrl"></a>
    </figure>
</div>

<p>Eagerly waiting for the results. 😄</p>
<p><strong>Update(24/04/2018)</strong>: Finally, I did not get into GSoC this time too. No worries. I anticipated the results and prepared backup plans. Looking forward to a productive summer. :)</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups" term="write-ups" label="Write-ups" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/cse" term="cse" label="CSE" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/foss" term="foss" label="FOSS" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[FOSSMeet'18]]></title>
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/fossmeet18/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/03/fossmeet17/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="FOSSMeet&#39;17" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/deactivated-my-facebook-account/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Deactivated My Facebook Account" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/why-a-sanskrit-shloka/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Why a Sanskrit Shloka?" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/searching-the-goal/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Searching the goal" />
            
                <id>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/fossmeet18/</id>
            
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Yash Agarwal</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2018-03-26T11:57:14+05:30</published>
            <updated>2018-03-26T11:57:14+05:30</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know I am very late in writing this post. It has been almost one and a half months since the last edition of FOSSMeet is over. I have been a part of FOSSMeet both as a participant and a volunteer. I want to share some of my observations, views, and suggestions through this post. I intend to keep a memory of my most favorite event of NIT Calicut. Juniors can read this post and think about ways to improve FOSSCell and FOSSMeet. I did the same by reading Kartik&rsquo;s <a href="http://techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/"><em>post</em></a>.</p>
<p>Before I start, if you have not read my <em>post</em> on the 2017 edition of the FOSSMeet, it is a good time to read that first. This post is going to be a follow up from where I stopped that post. <a href="/posts/2017/03/fossmeet17/">Here</a> is the link to that post.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ll start by quoting some lines from the last paragraph of that article.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I hope that I will find time next year for FOSSMeet, although I would prefer to attend FOSSMeet as a participant observing everything silently rather than being a part of the organizing team.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>These were my views after last year&rsquo;s FOSSMeet. I felt that I was not getting any benefit from volunteering for FOSSMeet. It is one thing that you help conducting an event, but on a personal level, I was not learning much. I wanted to attend talks and learn about free software philosophies, but because I was busy volunteering for workshops in <em>SSL</em>, I could not participate in any lecture. So I wanted to make sure that in my last FOSSMeet, I do attend all the talks and learn something new.</p>
<p>But fate had its plans for me. Few days after writing that post, Simsar, the coordinator of FOSSMeet &lsquo;17, came to my room and asked me if I would like to become the next secretary of FOSSCell. Those who don&rsquo;t know, FOSSCell is the group of people in NITC, who are supposed to work on free and open-source contribution. But it is not very active for the last few years. Probably the seniors decided to give me a chance because I was quite active in providing my suggestions for the FOSSCell when I was in the third year and had shown my intentions to reinitiate FOSSCell. Anyway, I was not very enthusiastic about this opportunity and <em>refused</em> to accept it. I thought that the topic was closed and did not bother about it much.</p>
<p>Fast forward two months, I was at home thinking about the reasons that I could not get an internship were. I figured out some reasons (a topic reserved for a later post!) and decided that whatever happens, I will not commit these mistakes again. A few days later, Simsar messaged me on WhatsApp, asking whether I am still interested in the post of secretary. This time, I immediately accepted his offer. I was under the influence of my learnings from past mistakes. And that&rsquo;s how I became the unexpected (at least for my batchmates) secretary of FOSSCell.</p>
<p>I was placed in the first few days of placement season, so I was free on that front. CSEA had conducted a Debian packaging workshop at the very beginning of the semester, but I could not attend that workshop. So I messaged Pirate Praveen sir privately and asked him whether he can guide me about Debian packaging. As with most of the senior open source contributors, he was very enthusiastic about helping me. So that&rsquo;s how I restarted my journey in open source. It was a fun time learning about free software ideology from Pirate Praveen. We decided to conduct a small Debian Packaging hackathon in NITC. As it is a norm in CSE NITC nowadays about any such activity, people did not turn up at all for this hackathon. Only five people showed up for the hackathon. That was disappointing. Though, on a personal level, I was satisfied. I submitted two packages to the Debian unstable repository. We did not have any other activity for the remaining of that semester.</p>
<p>Okay, enough of the background!</p>
<h2 id="my-observations">My Observations</h2>
<p>We opted for the <a href="https://talkfunnel.com">HasGeek&rsquo;s Funnel</a> for the proposal acceptance this time also. The funnel works quite well for our workflow. We did not get many <a href="https://fossmeet-nitc.talkfunnel.com/2018">proposals</a> in the beginning. I had read somewhere on the web that FOSSMeet had a MiniDebConf once. That seemed like an excellent idea to the team. So I talked with Praveen sir, about the possibility of a separate Debian track during FOSSMeet. I thought that Debian packaging might be a good and easy way to introduce NITC students to Open-source software.</p>
<p>In previous editions of FOSSMeets, the organizers used to receive the <a href="http://techglider.in/post/2013/04/14/of-fossmeets-at-nit-calicut/">feedback</a> that the student audience is entirely novice for some sessions and the supposedly advanced session turned out to be a beginner session. We were well aware of this problem and thought of a way to solve this. The solution may be a controversial one because even I have mixed feelings about this solution. We decided to look at the GitHub profiles of each participant and then select a few participants rather than allowing each and everyone who is paying money to attend the FOSSMeet. Our experience from last year was awful in this aspect. Students from various colleges of Kerala came to FOSSMeet just to get the certificate. Such an audience was not contributing anything to FOSSMeet.</p>
<p>Now, let me explain why I think that this is not the right way to filter good participants. If I am not wrong, one motive behind organizing such <em>student run conferences</em> is to inspire beginners and college students to learn about free and open-source software and to allow them to learn about new technologies. Now, it should not matter if the person has any prior experience or not. In our case, we prioritized the <em>previous experience</em> part and neglected <em>the will to learn</em>. I know that it is tough to identify if a person is really interested in the event or just coming for the certificate, but still, there must be some better way to solve this issue. For now, this method is the best option available, and it worked well enough for our purpose.</p>
<p>The decision to allow only 150 participants was an excellent move. We had decided not to have parallel workshops and talks. This decision was a direct outcome of some of the bad feedback from the previous FOSSMeets. The decisions to check GitHub profiles and to restrict the number of participants made sure that this edition of FOSSMeet has the most appropriate (read qualified) audience for any session.</p>
<p>We publicized the event among CSED&rsquo;s first years. We even had a beginner level Git workshop for them. We were expecting that they will come to take part in the event. These events provide excellent opportunities for newcomers to learn about Computer Science and its various fields. I used to give priority to a CSEA event over any cultural event when I was in my first year. But, the turnout of first-year students for FOSSMeet was very less. I sometimes worry, how are these people going to continue organizing FOSSMeet. In the end, conducting this event will become a burden (of carrying a legacy) for them, and they will hold this event just like any other useless event that happens in NITC every weekend. We even made the entry, free for them; still, if they don&rsquo;t feel interested in the event, then they are at an apparent loss.</p>
<p>One other complaint that we received from the community was that the procedure of selecting proposals from the funnel is not transparent. <em>In my opinion</em>, it is true. The organizing team of FOSSMeet sit together and choose the topics based on the relevance of the topics and its relation to FOSS ideologies. Most of the proposals in the funnel were related to some technology or programming language. We aimed to give a chance to the talks which explain more about free software in general. Most of the proposals selected this year revolved around this theme with one or two exceptions. But I think it might be a good idea to publicly tell the factors that are taken into account while selecting proposals. FOSSMeet is an event about free software and the community, and it is the responsibility of the organizers to make sure that they adhere to the ideologies of free software, including transparency.</p>
<p>The decision to select philosophical topics might seem like a great thing. Still, in reality, the student audience is not very interested in listening to some random guy preaching about something which is not very relevant to them. Students want more technical knowledge, which they can get only from technical talks and workshops. I hope that future FOSSMeet organizers will be more careful about maintaining the right balance between technical and not technical discussions and workshops.</p>
<p>Some students from Amrita college complained about our selection of the same speakers every year. In my opinion, it is a very valid complaint. In my last three FOSSMeets, almost 3-5 speakers are giving talks/workshops every year. I am not saying that it is bad in any way, but the organizing team can start a bit early and invite some other prominent faces of the field from different parts of the country. The issue is that we begin contacting speakers very late and the people coming from far corners of the country or from abroad get very little time for making arrangements.</p>
<p>We used to have panel discussions in FOSSMeet. For the last two years, we stopped having one. I think that a panel discussion is a great way to learn about different viewpoints of experienced people. It will be good if the future organizers can squeeze one such panel discussion in the FOSSMeet schedule.</p>
<p>Now coming to my memories of this edition of the event, I liked the video conference by Bradley M Kuhn, the president of the Software Freedom Conservancy. The way he explained current issues in software freedom was fascinating. I was amazed by his humbleness. I was looking forward to the talk by RMS, but he could not deliver his speech due to some technical issues.</p>
<p><strong>On a lighter note</strong>, It feels strange when you are working in a team where everyone except you speaks a language that you don&rsquo;t understand. I know that it is a very natural behavior, and I have no <em>complains</em> about it. But in my opinion, language is a tool of communication, and when you are not able to communicate your views to others, then there is some problem. When I think about these issues, I admire the forefathers of India for their farsightedness to make a <em>foreign</em> but <em>universal</em> language, one of the official languages of the Republic of India.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>I feel at a loss because I got the chance to attend only three FOSSMeets (2015 edition never came to reality). It has been a great experience both as a participant and a volunteer for me over the last three years. I have written two posts about FOSSMeets and have tried to cover everything which I liked or disliked about this event. I might be very <em>biased</em> in the views expressed here as I was very disappointed with the lack of any activity from the FOSSCell side to introduce students about open source contributions. My <em>lack</em> of good communication skills made sure that the trend continues in my tenure also. I wish good luck to the next office bearers and hope that they will not continue this trend. 😄</p>
<p>Thanks to all fourth years &ndash; Sajmal, <strong>Navaneeth</strong>, Nithin, Kumar, Pavithra, Vrushabh, Nitin, and others for making the FOSSMeet a success. All the best to all juniors &ndash; Abhiram, Archana, Olive, Amruth, Gazala, Abhirami, Anupam, Madhumita, Adil, Vysakh, Arun, and others. Special mention to some second years also &ndash; Nirmal, Faris, Darshana, Kavitha, Naina, Vishnu, and others for helping us out in a smooth organization of the event.</p>
<p>Feeling relieved now, as this long overdue post is finally complete. If you find the article interesting, share your views in the comments section. Thanks for reading. ☺</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups" term="write-ups" label="Write-ups" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/nitc" term="nitc" label="NITC" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/fossmeet" term="fossmeet" label="FOSSMeet" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/foss" term="foss" label="FOSS" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deactivated My Facebook Account]]></title>
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/deactivated-my-facebook-account/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/why-a-sanskrit-shloka/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Why a Sanskrit Shloka?" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/03/fossmeet17/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="FOSSMeet&#39;17" />
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/searching-the-goal/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Searching the goal" />
            
                <id>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/deactivated-my-facebook-account/</id>
            
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Yash Agarwal</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2018-03-23T21:00:44+05:30</published>
            <updated>2018-03-23T21:00:44+05:30</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I deactivated my Facebook account again. For the last few days, I was feeling that I am using Facebook excessively. It was affecting my work, my <em>public life</em>. I was using Facebook day in and day out. Today when I woke up in the morning, I first opened Facebook and didn&rsquo;t leave my bed for one hour. I realized that I had wasted one hour merely browsing through useless stuff. Immediately, I decided to deactivate the account for some time and analyze how much my life changes by one less distraction.</p>
<p>Coincidentally, it is the time of <a href="http://ragam.org.in/Main/">Ragam</a>, the annual cultural festival of NIT Calicut. I <em>introspect</em> myself every year at the same time. For the last two years, this introspection is resulting in the deactivation of my Facebook account. It is the reason why I could finish all my pending projects in the summers.</p>
<p>I sometimes feel that after coming to NITC, I have become much more socially awkward and even more of a loner than I was before. I never enjoyed going into public events, but in college, that tendency seems to have increased a lot. Now, I do not feel comfortable with this state. I want to change this, but every time I try, there is some <em>invisible force</em> which pulls me back from expressing myself. NITC&rsquo;s environment was entirely different for a person like me, who always preferred to stay alone. So, I built a <em>bubble</em> around myself, where there is no one to disturb or doubt me. It was okay in the initial years of my campus life when circumstances were not in my favor, but now this bubble is an obstacle for me. I feel difficulty in coming out of this bubble.</p>
<p>There are only one and a half months left of my undergraduate life. I might not overcome this fear at this time. But I hope that the change of environment will help me cross this barrier. I have learned a lot of lessons from my mistakes in the past, and I hope that I will not repeat one of the biggest mistakes of my life.</p>
<p>I will write again about the changes I feel after deactivating Facebook. In the meantime, I will try to spend more time with my friends and less on my laptop. 😌</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups" term="write-ups" label="Write-ups" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/nitc" term="nitc" label="NITC" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[My New Domain]]></title>
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/02/my-new-domain/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
            
                <id>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/02/my-new-domain/</id>
            
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Yash Agarwal</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2018-02-25T10:10:04+05:30</published>
            <updated>2018-02-25T10:10:04+05:30</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought a new domain a few days back - <em>yashagarwal.in</em>. I was trying to buy this domain for the last two years, but it was already taken. My previous domain, <em>yashagarwal.me</em> that I got for free via GitHub education pack, was good enough for me, but the thought that I own a domain which is a top-level domain of some other country was in itself something which was not comfortable to me. So when I got the chance to buy this domain, I didn&rsquo;t delay. Hope this domain will remain my personal home on the web for years to come.</p>
<p>The domain is mapped with GitLab, and the SSL certificates are provided by <a href="https://letsencrypt.org">Let&rsquo;s Encrypt</a>. Let&rsquo;s Encrypt requires you to renew the SSL certificates every 90 days. That seems like a manual work to me. Moreover, my new registrar, GoDaddy, provides a complete API for their domain services. So I am planning to write a script that utilizes the APIs of <a href="https://gitlab.com/help/api/README.md">GitLab</a> and <a href="https://developer.godaddy.com/">GoDaddy</a> to deploy the SSL certificates automatically. I will probably use the DNS based authentication to verify the ownership of my domain, as that seems the only method that does not require any modification on the host side. I will write a post with all the details about the script, once I finish implementing it.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s all for this post. See you next time. :)</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups" term="write-ups" label="Write-ups" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[2017 - The Best Till Now]]></title>
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/12/2017-the-best-till-now/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
            
                <id>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/12/2017-the-best-till-now/</id>
            
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Yash Agarwal</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2017-12-31T23:19:00+05:30</published>
            <updated>2017-12-31T23:19:00+05:30</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[



    

    
    

    
    <link rel="stylesheet" href="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/photoswipe/4.1.1/photoswipe.min.css" integrity="sha256-sCl5PUOGMLfFYctzDW3MtRib0ctyUvI9Qsmq2wXOeBY=" crossorigin="anonymous" />
    <link rel="stylesheet" href="https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/photoswipe/4.1.1/default-skin/default-skin.min.css" integrity="sha256-BFeI1V+Vh1Rk37wswuOYn5lsTcaU96hGaI7OUVCLjPc=" crossorigin="anonymous" />

    
    <link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/photoswipe.min.d780348a887d97b4d6cc664301a2941706e4a02aeb1533524fcce3b7b9b64b4f.css">

    

    
    <div class="pswp" tabindex="-1" role="dialog" aria-hidden="true">
        
        <div class="pswp__bg"></div>
        
        <div class="pswp__scroll-wrap">
            
            <div class="pswp__container">
                <div class="pswp__item"></div>
                <div class="pswp__item"></div>
                <div class="pswp__item"></div>
            </div>
            
            <div class="pswp__ui pswp__ui--hidden">
                <div class="pswp__top-bar">
                    
                    <div class="pswp__counter"></div>
                    <button class="pswp__button pswp__button--close" title="Close (Esc)"></button>
                    <button class="pswp__button pswp__button--share" title="Share"></button>
                    <button class="pswp__button pswp__button--fs" title="Toggle fullscreen"></button>
                    <button class="pswp__button pswp__button--zoom" title="Zoom in/out"></button>
                    
                    
                    <div class="pswp__preloader">
                        <div class="pswp__preloader__icn">
                            <div class="pswp__preloader__cut">
                                <div class="pswp__preloader__donut"></div>
                            </div>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div class="pswp__share-modal pswp__share-modal--hidden pswp__single-tap">
                    <div class="pswp__share-tooltip"></div>
                </div>
                <button class="pswp__button pswp__button--arrow--left" title="Previous (arrow left)">
                </button>
                <button class="pswp__button pswp__button--arrow--right" title="Next (arrow right)">
                </button>
                <div class="pswp__caption">
                    <div class="pswp__caption__center"></div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

<p>If I have to define 2017 in one word, that would be amazing. This year has been a life-changing year for me. I learned a lot of new things, had some excellent experience in the company of amazing people, had a great time in my academic life and SSL. 2017 has been a very significant year for me, and I want to record this memory by documenting some of the most amazing things that I learned and experienced this year.</p>
<h2 id="grades">Grades</h2>
<p>Although I cared very little for grades for the most of my college life, this year changed my perception of grades. I finally understood that the grades are also equally important. I started <em>2017</em> with only one goal &mdash; getting good grades. I studied a lot in the first half of the year, and it is because of that time, I hold an excellent command over Computer Networks. If I have to choose any one semester for my placement, It would be 6th semester.</p>
<p>I invested most of my time for preparation of campus placements in the mid of the year. Reading Data Structures and Algorithms have proven to be very beneficial for me. However, the way I studied Data Structures, hasn&rsquo;t improved my skills in real-world problem-solving skills.</p>
<p>I did not do exceptionally well in academics in the late half of the year. Partly because of the <em>after placement</em> and <em>&ldquo;Dude, it is fourth year&rdquo;</em> type of environment around me. My final year project did not go in the right direction, and it is one of the very few disappointments for me in <em>2017</em>.</p>
<h2 id="coding">Coding</h2>
<p>It is one thing which I could never excel in my undergrad life. People say that coding is a skill and it requires practice. However, to continue doing that practice, one needs patience, that, unfortunately, I lack. This year continued to be the same as 2016. I could not overcome my fear of coding. I tried doing something different in the form of <a href="https://twitter.com/_100DaysOfCode">#100daysofcode</a>, but couldn&rsquo;t continue it after 20 days because of my preparations for campus placements. I have again started writing code on a regular basis in late December. Looking forward to code more frequently in 2018.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/TheYashAgarwal?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@theyashagarwal</a> is one of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/supercoder?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#supercoder</a> of the day. Good work. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/100DaysOfCode?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#100DaysOfCode</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/301DaysOfCode?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#301DaysOfCode</a></p>&mdash; SuperCoderBot (@heroes_bot) <a href="https://twitter.com/heroes_bot/status/873491081173897216?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 10, 2017</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Recently I started working on Debian Packaging. <a href="http://civic.gnu.org.in/author/praveen">Praveen</a> sir has always been very supportive of me and answered all my ludicrous questions very patiently. My conversation with him about free software philosophy has been very enlightening. Debian Packaging was a very satisfying experience to be able to give something back to the community. Now, I hold <a href="https://qa.debian.org/developer.php?login=yashagarwaljpr@gmail.com">one</a> package in the unstable Debian repository and <a href="https://qa.debian.org/developer.php?login=bansaly26@gmail.com">two</a> more packages in the pipeline for approval.</p>






<div class="gallery caption-position-bottom caption-effect-slide hover-effect-zoom hover-transition" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageGallery">
        
    


    <link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/hugo-easy-gallery.css">
    


<div class="box fancy-figure caption-position-bottom caption-effect-appear"  itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageGallery">
    <figure  itemprop="associatedMedia" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject">
        <div class="img" style="background-image: url('https://yashagarwal.in//images/posts/2017-12-31/HackFest1.jpg');">
            <img itemprop="thumbnail" src="/images/posts/2017-12-31/HackFest1.jpg" alt="Working on my first Debian package"/>
        </div>
        <a href="/images/posts/2017-12-31/HackFest1.jpg" itemprop="contentUrl"></a>
            <figcaption>
                    <p>Working on my first Debian package</p>
            </figcaption>
    </figure>
</div>

    


<div class="box fancy-figure caption-position-bottom caption-effect-appear"  itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageGallery">
    <figure  itemprop="associatedMedia" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject">
        <div class="img" style="background-image: url('https://yashagarwal.in//images/posts/2017-12-31/HackFest2.jpg');">
            <img itemprop="thumbnail" src="/images/posts/2017-12-31/HackFest2.jpg" alt="Praveen sir and team"/>
        </div>
        <a href="/images/posts/2017-12-31/HackFest2.jpg" itemprop="contentUrl"></a>
            <figcaption>
                    <p>Praveen sir and team</p>
            </figcaption>
    </figure>
</div>


</div>
<h2 id="placement">Placement</h2>
<p>I joined NIT Calicut due to many <a href="http://dsanghi.blogspot.in/2011/05/my-2011-list-of-recommended-csit.html">reasons</a>. Placements were undoubtedly one of the most important of them. Fortunately, I was among first few students to get placed in my batch. That moment came with a great relief in my life.</p>



<div class="box fancy-figure caption-position-bottom caption-effect-appear"  itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageGallery">
    <figure  itemprop="associatedMedia" itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject">
        <div class="img">
            <img itemprop="thumbnail" src="/images/posts/2017-12-31/placement.png#center" alt="A private post on FB, now public"/>
        </div>
        <a href="/images/posts/2017-12-31/placement.png#center" itemprop="contentUrl"></a>
            <figcaption>
                    <p>A private post on FB, now public</p>
            </figcaption>
    </figure>
</div>

<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<p>I had started this year with an aim to read ten books and keep track of my reading on <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/8390620">Goodreads</a>. In the end, I could not finish my goal. I did occasionally try to meet my goal, but my excessive reliance on soft copies of the books always distracted me. Now, it is not a surprise that I am unable to read anything on a screen. I got three hard copy books and finished two of them. However, I could not go past more than 20 pages of any digital book, that I bought on Kindle.</p>
<h2 id="writing">Writing</h2>
<p>I have not written for the most of the year. I do think about writing occasionally and keep a note of all the ideas that I get. However, due to my busy schedule and my usual procrastination, I do not write that often. In 2018, I will try to write more often.</p>
<h2 id="health">Health</h2>
<p>It is one issue where I do not put enough stress. I can divide my year into two parts for this portion. Pre Birthday half and post Birthday half. I maintained a daily exercise routine for the first half of the year. That helped me in many ways. I felt more energetic, more productive and more resolute to troubles in life. I slept at ten each day and woke up early morning. It resulted in excellent health, which I had always lacked.</p>
<p>However, the second half of the year was disastrous. Due to weather and other unavoidable circumstances, I could not keep up my routine; once I came back to college. I started sleeping late again, and that resulted in me going to docter very often in the last two months.</p>
<h2 id="relations">Relations</h2>
<p>I continued to feel bored in the company of people. It is somewhat strange that after getting into college, year by year, my interest in public events has decreased gradually. It may be because of the difference in my understanding of happiness and that of others.</p>
<p>I built good relations with some faculties in the <a href="http://cse.nitc.ac.in">Department</a>, my technical skills got me some admirers, who eventually became my <em>friends</em>. I made some new friends from MCA also this year. It has been a pleasant experience overall.</p>
<p><strong><em>Looking forward to 2018 for, full of new experiences!</em></strong></p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups" term="write-ups" label="Write-ups" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/review" term="review" label="review" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[FOSSMeet'17]]></title>
            <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/03/fossmeet17/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/searching-the-goal/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Searching the goal" />
            
                <id>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/03/fossmeet17/</id>
            
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Yash Agarwal</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2017-03-13T21:03:16+00:00</published>
            <updated>2017-03-13T21:03:16+00:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One more edition of FOSSMeet&rsquo;17 was successfully organized in NIT Calicut recently. As an active member of the organizing team of this year&rsquo;s edition (though I sidelined myself at the end) and a keen but silent observer, I want to share my experience, ideas, and some observations through this post.</p>
<h2 id="marketing-website">Marketing Website</h2>
<p>We started planning the next edition of FOSSMeet sometime around September. Not many people were interested in planning. Anyway, Shrimadhav and I began working on the marketing website. The first design was straightaway rejected by Piyush and Simsar, which I feel, was fruitful. In the process, I learned some critical insights about planning, team management, and design of a user-friendly website. So I again started working on the site. The end product was clean, good looking, and simple (at least I was happy with it :P).</p>
<p>In the meanwhile, Amal and I started thinking about ideas, how can we restructure the FOSSCell, which had not seen a single activity (except those trademark events which were conducted just for formality) in years. I now understand that it was a mistake. It is a prerequisite about open source contribution that you should contribute to the products which you use in day to day life. When we started thinking about the FOSSCell, we didn&rsquo;t know about any of these points. We conducted a formal test(more of a filtering process), then we had a small meeting with the selected 2nd years about the FOSSCell, and we discussed the plan for next semester. Then everyone left for winter vacations.</p>
<h2 id="a-period-of-self-evaluation">A period of self-evaluation</h2>
<p>In the winter holidays, we tried to have some IRC discussions, which again was somewhat successful because of the efforts from Shrimadhav and Simsar. It was a new experience for me also, but still, I tried to attend as much as I could. I also took one session on Git and Vim, which again was an entirely new experience for me.</p>
<p>In the winter vacation, I found some time to think about the purpose of FOSSMeet and FOSSCell and in what direction we were heading. I somehow understood that I was not qualified enough to guide someone about open source contribution or in general FOSS ideology, because I, myself was not contributing anything to open source community, and had no characteristic of a FOSS enthusiast. So I somehow lost my interest in FOSSCell and even in Linux. Shrimadhav asked me my ideas about FOSSCell activities, but I had no clue what to say. So that&rsquo;s how the FOSSCell again died without achieving anything significant. I feel it was my mistake. I still feel sad about this. :(</p>
<h2 id="fossmeet-time">FOSSMeet time</h2>
<p>So as the FOSSMeet&rsquo;s dates came near, people started coming for <em>volunteering</em>. It was good for the event, though. The funnel was already up last semester, and we were getting some good proposals also. FOSSMeet also went superbly. All the participants gave excellent reviews. There were some hiccups also, The Campus Internet Connectivity being the most significant one. There were some issues in SSL also, again, somewhere I hold an important responsibility. All in all, everybody praised the event and organization of the event. This year, we tried to reduce the use of plastics, and I feel that we were quite successful.</p>
<h2 id="my-observations">My Observations</h2>
<p>There were some issues about the event, which I didn&rsquo;t like at a personal level. I sometimes think about what is the motive for conducting some activities in colleges. An event like FOSSMeet which attract the attention of all FOSS enthusiasts from all over Kerala has a huge potential of inspiring the young folks of NIT Calicut. We somehow succeed in that motive, but what about the situation after FOSSMeet. The enthusiasm about FOSS should not last just for two days, but we cannot blame others for the condition. I don&rsquo;t have a proper idea about the FOSS because there was no proper guidance from my senior batches. I learned many things in the workshops organized by CSEA, in fact, I first learned the proper use of Linux Shell in the Linux workshop conducted by CSEA (and FOSSCell, at least for formality). But you can&rsquo;t ask them to do everything. I think they are already overloaded. But there were no such workshops by FOSSCell.</p>
<p>Second, the curriculum of the NITC CSE department focuses more on the theoretical side of Computer Science, which is good. But it negatively affects student activities outside the classroom. That is one of the primary reasons why we cannot produce more GSoC participants or why don&rsquo;t we have more open source enthusiasts.</p>
<p>Third, one of the speakers in FOSSMeet mentioned one fundamental flaw in the structure of the organizing team of FOSSMeet. It doesn&rsquo;t have any representation from other branches. FOSSMeet has become an event for CSE folks, where people from different departments do not take any interest. I think publicity was a major issue here. I don&rsquo;t believe that there was any publicity done to explain FOSSMeet to the students of other branches. (If I am wrong here, please correct me).</p>
<p>Fourth, people are ready to <em>volunteer</em> for organizing an event, but they do not want to come and attend the workshops. FOSSMeet is held by individuals who have no previous experience of FOSS and have no intention to dive into open source community any time soon. FOSSMeet has become a tradition that is continued every year because it happened the previous year also. I do not feel that enthusiasm to promote FOSS in FOSSMeet because we are organizing it to keep the legacy. I am not saying that whatever effort organizers put in conducting FOSSMeet&rsquo;17 was not significant. I am not the right person to blame them because I was also part of the same team. But still, I feel that FOSSMeet has lost its original motive to promote FOSS culture in NITC. It encourages more people from outside NITC, but inside NITC, it is just one of those many events organized by random clubs.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>It&rsquo;s been an interesting one year for me after becoming SS Lab Admin because I started taking part in department activities that I always wanted to do. Being a member of the organizing team of FOSSMeet&rsquo;17 was again a learning experience for me. I learned many new things, in SSL and outside SSL too. I committed some mistakes also in making the right decisions at the right moment, but that&rsquo;s how I learn. So no regrets. :) I hope that I will find time next year for FOSSMeet, although I would prefer to attend FOSSMeet as a participant observing everything silently rather than being a part of the organizing team.</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/write-ups" term="write-ups" label="Write-ups" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/nitc" term="nitc" label="NITC" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/foss" term="foss" label="FOSS" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://yashagarwal.in/tags/fossmeet" term="fossmeet" label="FOSSMeet" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
</feed>
