<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arch-linux on /dev/yash/notes</title>
    <link>https://yashhere.github.io/categories/arch-linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Arch-linux on /dev/yash/notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 21:49:05 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yashhere.github.io/categories/arch-linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux Installation Guide Part 1</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2018/01/arch-linux-installation-guide-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 21:49:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2018/01/arch-linux-installation-guide-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Arch Linux is a Linux distribution known for its not-so-beginner-friendly command line installer, no ready-to-use system after installation and requirement of above average knowledge of command line. However, Arch Linux allows me to set up a system in my desired state in shortest possible time with least effort. This is why I keep coming back to Arch Linux even after some of its annoyances.
This guide is written primarily for my reference, as someone who has installed Arch Linux several times, I still can&amp;rsquo;t remember all the installation steps perfectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Arch Linux setup with Openbox</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2016/06/custom-arch-linux-setup-with-openbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2016/06/custom-arch-linux-setup-with-openbox/</guid>
      <description>After my summer vacation started, I bought a new laptop and the first thing I did was to install Arch Linux on it. After a standard arch installation procedure, I started putting together my own desktop environment starting with ArchLinux and Openbox and then piecing all pieces together to build a proper desktop environment. Building a desktop this way really follows the Unix Methodology; have softwares that each do one thing well, and when you put them together you get something amazing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>