<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Configuration on /dev/yash/notes</title>
    <link>https://yashhere.github.io/tags/configuration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Configuration on /dev/yash/notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 21:49:05 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yashhere.github.io/tags/configuration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux Installation Guide Part 1</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2018/01/arch-linux-installation-guide-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 21:49:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2018/01/arch-linux-installation-guide-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Arch Linux is a Linux distribution known for its not-so-beginner-friendly command line installer, no ready-to-use system after installation and requirement of above average knowledge of command line. However, Arch Linux allows me to set up a system in my desired state in shortest possible time with least effort. This is why I keep coming back to Arch Linux even after some of its annoyances.
This guide is written primarily for my reference, as someone who has installed Arch Linux several times, I still can&amp;rsquo;t remember all the installation steps perfectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up SSH Agent in i3</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/12/setting-up-ssh-agent-in-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 20:21:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/12/setting-up-ssh-agent-in-i3/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will write about the procedure to correctly setup SSH and GPG agents in the i3 window manager. To follow this post, you need to have ssh-keys and your private GPG keys ready. If you do not already have these keys with you, I will describe the process of creating the keys.
SSH Generating an SSH key pair provides you with a public key and a private key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up ALM Octane with Docker Compose.</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/12/setting-up-alm-octane-with-docker-compose./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 20:53:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/12/setting-up-alm-octane-with-docker-compose./</guid>
      <description>Recently, I got a chance to setup ALM Octane on one of my university server for a course project. From the support page of ALM Octane:
 ALM Octane is a web-based application lifecycle management platform that enables teams to collaborate easily, manage the product delivery pipeline, and visualise the impact of changes.
 Precursor My department insists on using open source software (a plus point, indeed !). But ALM Octane has Oracle DB/MSSQL as a dependency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Hindi Fonts in Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/10/fixing-hindi-fonts-in-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 21:55:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/10/fixing-hindi-fonts-in-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>When viewing Hindi content in any browser in Arch Linux, the rendering looks weird.
Doesn&amp;rsquo;t look good right! I&amp;rsquo;ll try to fix this issue in this post. You might need to install the appropriate font support in Arch Linux before applying this fix. The appropriate package for installing Indic Language support is ttf-indic-otf.
Now go to /usr/share/fonts/TTF and take the backup of two fonts FreeSans.ttf and FreeSerif.ttf. Now delete these two fonts from the directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mounting NTFS partitions on Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/03/mounting-ntfs-partitions-on-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 10:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashhere.github.io/posts/2017/03/mounting-ntfs-partitions-on-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I installed Arch Linux once again. A clean, bloat free desktop with Budgie Desktop environment with some must have open source tools. Everything worked fine except WiFi and some minor bugs in Budgie(I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether it is a bug in Budgie or just a wrong setting). I also faced the problem of mounting Windows NTFS volumes on user&amp;rsquo;s wish. Arch Linux wiki has details about how to auto mount partitions on start-up, but I had a tough time to find out what exactly needs to be done to simulate the behavior of Ubuntu-like distribution on the mounting of NTFS drives.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>