<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experience on /dev/yash/notes</title>
    <link>https://yashagarwal.in/categories/experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Experience on /dev/yash/notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution - NonCommercial - ShareAlike 4.0 International</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 22:02:08 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 - Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/12/2018-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 22:02:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/12/2018-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>The year 2018 has been quite a roller coaster year for me. I saw many ups and downs, many successes and many failures, faced many challenges on the personal front and struggled to keep myself on track. I have been working hard on improving my lifestyle (not materialistically) for the last few years, and the benefits have begun to show up now. This year was a pinnacle in that aspect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning a New Journey</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/08/beginning-a-new-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 21:16:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/08/beginning-a-new-journey/</guid>
      <description>When I was in eighth (or was it ninth?) class, one of our teachers asked in the class, what do you want to become in your life? People said a lot of things. When my turn came up, I stood up and said, “Mein software engineer banana chahta hu” (I want to become a software engineer). It was not that I was genuinely interested in Computers. When I look back now, I realize that it was my cousins who affected my choice (in an indirect way) and their achievements fascinated me to aim at this particular career choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Good and Bad about CSED of NIT-C</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/the-good-and-bad-about-csed-of-nit-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 17:59:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/the-good-and-bad-about-csed-of-nit-c/</guid>
      <description>Four years ago, in this very month of June, JEE Mains results were out. I had screwed up my JEE Advanced, so I had to settle for an NIT. My AIR was good enough to get me a seat of Computer Science and Engineering in any of the NITs except the first three (at that time Trichy, Warangal, and Surathkal). I was skeptical about going to NIT Calicut because of its distance from my native place, so NIT Allahabad was the most suitable choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistakes That I Made in NITC</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/mistakes-that-i-made-in-nitc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:21:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/06/mistakes-that-i-made-in-nitc/</guid>
      <description>Now that I am graduated from NIT Calicut, one more chapter of my life is over. It is time to move on to the next page, but before I begin that phase, I thought it would be nice, to sum up, the experience that I gathered in NIT Calicut. The last four years have been great for me. I learned a lot of new life lessons, but there were some decisions which I could have avoided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So I Applied for GSoC</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/so-i-applied-for-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 20:58:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/so-i-applied-for-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>I first heard about Google Summer of Code (GSoC) in my second year (2016). It was quite fascinating to know that such a program exists (possibly because of that super attractive amount of money, $5500 at that time). I researched about it and sent emails to some mentors. The replies were mostly encouraging, but I still could not gather the courage to apply as I used to doubt my capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSSMeet&#39;18</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/fossmeet18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 11:57:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/fossmeet18/</guid>
      <description>I know I am very late in writing this post. It has been almost one and half months since the last edition of FOSSMeet is over. I have been a part of FOSSMeet both as a participant and a volunteer. I want to share some of my observations, views, and suggestions through this post. I intend to keep a memory of my most favorite event of NIT Calicut. Juniors can read this post and think about ways to improve FOSSCell and FOSSMeet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deactivated My Facebook Account</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/deactivated-my-facebook-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 21:00:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/deactivated-my-facebook-account/</guid>
      <description>Today, I deactivated my Facebook account again. For last few days, I started feeling that I am using Facebook excessively. That was affecting some other works. It was even affecting my public life. I was using Facebook day in and day out. Today when I woke up in the morning, I first opened Facebook and didn&amp;rsquo;t leave my bed for one hour. I realized that I have wasted one hour merely browsing through useless stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why a Sanskrit Shloka?</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/why-a-sanskrit-shloka/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 20:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/01/why-a-sanskrit-shloka/</guid>
      <description>श्रूयतां धर्मसर्वस्वं श्रुत्वा चाप्यवधार्यताम्।
आत्मनः प्रतिकूलानि परेषां न समाचरेत्।। If the entire Dharma can be said in a few words, then it is — that which is unfavorable to us, do not do that to others.
— Padmapuraana, shrushti 19/357–358
 So when you landed on this blog, the first thing you might have noticed is that the home page of this blog has a Sanskrit shloka. Many people ask me, why did I choose to display a Sanskrit shloka on my blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 - The Best Till Now</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/12/2017-the-best-till-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 23:19:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/12/2017-the-best-till-now/</guid>
      <description>If I have to define 2017 in one word, that would be amazing. This year has been a life-changing year for me. I learned a lot of new things, had some excellent experience in the company of amazing people, had a great time in my academic life and SSL. 2017 has been a very significant year for me, and I want to record this memory by documenting some of the most amazing things that I learned and experienced this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSSMeet&#39;17</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/03/fossmeet17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 21:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/03/fossmeet17/</guid>
      <description>One more edition of FOSSMeet&amp;rsquo;17 was successfully organized in NIT Calicut recently. As an active member of the organizing team of this year&amp;rsquo;s edition (though I sidelined myself at the end) and a keen but silent observer, I want to share my experience, ideas, and some observations through this post.
Marketing Website We started planning next edition of FOSSMeet sometime around September. Not many people were interested in the planning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching the goal</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/searching-the-goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/searching-the-goal/</guid>
      <description>A boy, probably of age 16, just cleared his 10th board exam. He saw people working on computers, and that fascinated him. So he had only one ambition. You got it, right? One fine day, suddenly his friend&amp;#8217;s mother asked, &amp;#8220; So what about the future? You are going to enter in class 11th. It is the right time to decide about your future. What do you want to become, a doctor or an engineer?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>