<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on /dev/yash/notes</title>
    <link>https://yashagarwal.in/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on /dev/yash/notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 20:58:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yashagarwal.in/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>So I Applied for GSoC</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/so-i-applied-for-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 20:58:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/so-i-applied-for-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>I first heard about Google Summer of Code (GSoC) in my second year (2016). It was quite fascinating to know that such a program exists (possibly because of that super attractive amount of money, $5500 at that time). I researched about it and sent emails to some mentors. The replies were mostly encouraging, but I still could not gather the courage to apply as I used to doubt my capabilities. Then last year (2017) again, I decided that I should try for GSoC one more time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop a Theme for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/develop-a-theme-for-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 11:27:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2018/03/develop-a-theme-for-hugo/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published on zeolearn.
Introduction In this tutorial, I will show you how to create a basic Hugo theme. I assume that you are familiar with basic HTML, and how to write content in markdown. I will be explaining the working of Hugo and how it uses Go templating language and how you can use these templates to organize your content. As this post will be focusing mainly on Hugo&amp;rsquo;s working, I will not be covering CSS here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Hugo automatic deployment to Github with Wercker</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/02/setting-up-hugo-automatic-deployment-to-github-with-wercker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 13:37:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2017/02/setting-up-hugo-automatic-deployment-to-github-with-wercker/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I again migrated my blog from Pelican to Hugo. So till now, I have experimented with Wordpress, Jekyll, Pelican and Hugo. Without any doubt, Hugo is the simplest to setup. This time, I have setup Hugo in Windows, as I think, in my system, I reinstall Windows OS much less frequently than the Linux. So that way, it will be less pain for me to set up the blog again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A good Sublime Text Setup</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/a-good-sublime-text-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 10:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/posts/2016/04/a-good-sublime-text-setup/</guid>
      <description>So, after a hactic day, a good news finally came. I have been selected as a Lab Administrator for the Software Systems Lab of my college. Cheers!!!
Let&amp;#8217;s come to our today&amp;#8217;s topic on configuring Sublime Text Settings.
There is just one rule you must follow while designing your own editor preference configuration.
 Don&amp;#8217;t put any lines in your configuration that you don&amp;#8217;t understand.
 You will find tons of online tutorials that contains all kinds of awesome hacks to make your sublime text experience better but the worst way to make your development environment better is to just borrow the configuration from someone else.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>