<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Readings on /dev/yash/notes</title>
    <link>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Readings on /dev/yash/notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution - NonCommercial - ShareAlike 4.0 International</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 09:50:27 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yashagarwal.in/readings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Millionaire Booklet - Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018-12-17-the-millionaire-booklet-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 09:50:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018-12-17-the-millionaire-booklet-review/</guid>
      <description>Rating: 3.7 / 5 
A friend suggested me to read this book. It was my first audiobook, and my experience is a mixed one. I am not a very good retainer of information while listening to something when compared with my retention capabilities while reading. So I do not know how much I will be able to carry forward from this book. However, there are some cool bits of advice in this book, which contradict with my beliefs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Will Teach You to Be Rich - Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018-12-16-i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 08:30:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018-12-16-i-will-teach-you-to-be-rich-review/</guid>
      <description>Rating: 4 / 5 
It was my first book on the topic of personal finance. I am entirely new to managing money, so I thought it would be a good idea to gain some knowledge before trying anything crazy. I must say, this book has not disappointed me. I do not know, how other personal-finance books are written, but from my point of view, I learned a lot by reading this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Code Book - Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018-12-15-the-code-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 19:04:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018-12-15-the-code-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Rating: 5 / 5 
I was interested in Cryptography and Number Theory during my undergraduate studies so reading the history of Cryptography in this book was intriguing for me. The author has done excellent work in making sure that even an uninitiated person in Cryptography can understand and appreciate the importance of work done in this field. The people unequipped with the necessary background knowledge will enjoy this book as much as the math nerds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Secrets of Vishnu - Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018-11-24-7-secrets-of-vishnu-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 14:00:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018-11-24-7-secrets-of-vishnu-review/</guid>
      <description>Rating: 4.5 / 5 
For me, reading this book was to look at the things that I already knew, from a different perspective — not necessarily the view that I agree with. This book starts with Mohini and goes on to tell the stories of all the mainstream avatars of Vishnu and what the significance of those avatars was, in their respective time periods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Quantum Theory - Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018-11-18-introducing-quantum-theory-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 20:31:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018-11-18-introducing-quantum-theory-review/</guid>
      <description>Rating: 4.2 / 5 
There was a time when I used to despise Physics. I still do not know the exact reason behind this feeling because I was much interest in Physics in general. Perhaps the mathematical questions of JEE put me off.
I picked this book thinking that it will have something related to Quantum Computing (I am pretty much new to this area of CS), but I was entirely wrong in my guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rozabal Line - Review</title>
      <link>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018-11-05-book-review-the-rozabal-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 12:00:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yashagarwal.in/readings/2018-11-05-book-review-the-rozabal-line/</guid>
      <description>Rating: 3.8 / 5 
It was an exciting read for me. I must say the amount of research done by the author is really commendable. Given the topic of this work, the author comes very close to getting everything right, but eventually, he misses the mark.
I have a bit of interest in Hindu mythology, so I had a bias before going for this book.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>